<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<!DOCTYPE article SYSTEM "geexbox.dtd">

<article>

  <define name="paypal">
    <center>
      <p>
        <object>
          <form id="_xclick" action="https://www.paypal.com/cgi-bin/webscr" method="post">
            <p>
              <input type="hidden" name="cmd" value="_xclick"/>
              <input type="hidden" name="business" value="donate@geexbox.org"/>
              <input type="hidden" name="item_name" value="Contribution to a free software"/>
              <input type="hidden" name="return" value="http://www.geexbox.org/"/>
              <input type="hidden" name="currency_code" value="EUR"/>
              <input type="hidden" name="lc" value="US"/>
              <input type="image" src="http://www.paypal.com/en_US/i/btn/x-click-butcc-donate.gif" name="submit" alt="Donate" title="Make payments with PayPal - it's fast, free and secure!"/>
            </p>
          </form>
        </object>
      </p>
    </center>
  </define>

  <define name="vboard">
* ATI Rage 128 Ultra 32M AGP TV<br/>
* ATI Rage 128 Pro AGP<br/>
* ATI Rage 128 AGP<br/>
* SiS 6326 8M AGP<br/>
* SiS 6326 4M AGP<br/>
* S3 Trio 64V+<br/>
* S3 Trio 368 8M AGP<br/>
* S3 Trio 32 PCI<br/>
* 3Dfx Voodoo 3 8M PCI<br/>
* Diamond Viper V550 (nVidia TnT) 16M AGP TV<br/>
  </define>

  <define name="soundcard">
* SB 128 CT4810 PCI<br/>
* SB Live! CT4830<br/>
* Yamaha WaveForce 192XG<br/>
  </define>

  <define name="misc">
* Tekram DC-310/310U PCI SCSI<br/>
* Adaptec AHA-2920 PCI SCSI<br/>
* Cnet WiFi 54 Mbps USB dongle WD-854<br/>
* Pinnacle Studio PCTV Pro BT848<br/>
* 3COM 10Mbps LAN PC-Card<br/>
* US Robotics PCMCIA V.34 Modem<br/>
* Hauppauge PVR 350<br/>
  </define>

  <define name="computer">
* Macintosh iMac G3<br/>
* EPIA MII-1000<br/>
* Microsoft XboX<br/>
* HP e-Vectra<br/>
* DELL Latitude C510 / C610<br/>
* SGI O2<br/>
  </define>

  <define name="response-computing-url">
    <a href="http://www.responsecomputing.co.uk">Response Computing</a>
  </define>

  <define name="westminster-url">
    <a href="http://www.wg-plc.com/">IT Manager, Westminster Group PLC</a>
  </define>

  <define name="donators">
    <i>Romain Perea, Luigi Bortolani, Sam Huffman, Clint Brothers, Paul François, Lobo Martinez, Olivier Cochard, Laurent Peltier, Jonathan Davis, Michaël Berlioz-Arthaud.</i>
  </define>

  <define name="donators-hard">
    Sylvain Doctrinal, Coyot, Lolo, Nicolas Jolly, Cédric Chaissac, Andrew Florence (<use name="response-computing-url"/>), Guy C. McNeill (<use name="westminster-url"/>)
  </define>

  <section label="donate">
    <content lang="en" title="Donate ..."/>
    <content lang="fr" title="Donations ..."/>
    <content lang="de" title="Spenden ..."/>

    <subsection label="donate_why">
      <content lang="en" title="Why donate ?">
      GeeXboX is a free project, developed by people with their free time. This means that we have no income or support to help us with development. Many users request new features from us, especially on hardware we do not own. Besides, hosting the web server, the domain name and providing the needed bandwidth to let you download GeeXboX's ISO has a cost. Recently, we've been lucky that someone has provided us a free webserver but this may change at any time.
      </content>
      <content lang="fr" title="Pourquoi faire un don ?">
      GeeXboX est un projet libre, développé par des bénévoles sur leur temps libre. Cela signifie que nous ne touchons aucun revenu, profit ou subventions qui pourrait nous aider à développer. De nombreux utilisateurs nous demande de nouvelles fonctionnalités, particulièrement le support de matériel que nous ne possédons pas. De plus, héberger le serveur web, le nom de domaine et fournir la bande passante requise pour vous permettre de télécharger la GeeXboX, a un coût non négligeable. A l'heure actuelle, nous avons de la chance qu'un généreux contributeur nous ais fourni un serveur web gratuitement, mais cette situation peut changer à n'importe quel moment.
      </content>
      <content lang="de" title="Warum Spenden ?">
      GeeXboX ist ein "freies" Projekt und wird von verschiedenen Leuten in deren Freizeit entwickelt. Dies bedeutet, dass wir kein Einkommen oder eine andere Unterstützung für die Entwicklung erhalten. Viele Benutzer fragen nach Verbesserungen, speziell für ihre Hardware, die wir aber selbst nicht besitzen. Neben der Bereitstellung des Webservers, des Domänennamens und der benötigten Bandbreite, damit Sie das GeeXboX ISO herunterladen können, entstehen uns weitere Kosten. Seit kurzem haben wir das Glück, dass uns ein Webserver kostenlos zur Verfügung steht, aber dies kann sich jederzeit auch wieder ändern.
      </content>
    </subsection>

    <subsection label="donate_how">
      <content lang="en" title="How can I help or donate ?">
      To donate does not necessarily mean giving money. Of course, if you really like GeeXboX and believe that the time used to develop it should be rewarded, your money donations are welcomed (they will be used to help meet goals requested from users, such as having better development conditions, i.e buying new hardware to add support ...). If you want to contribute to the GeeXboX project you can make a donation using <b>PayPal</b> : it's free, easy and of course you're free to donate what you think our work deserves. The whole development team thanks you.<br/><br/>

<use name="paypal"/>

But you're also able to help us from many others ways. If you can provide us dedicated servers, bandwidth, promotions, advertisement, or even specific piece of hardware, old computers stuff, please contact us, your help will be greatly welcomed. By the way, you can also help us with your own skills as we're looking for translations maintainers, documentation maintainers and especially designers and drawers.<br/><br/>

At the moment, we're really looking for specific help :<br/><br/>
* lots of hardware bits (even old ones) to add support to GeeXboX (video cards, sound cards ...).<br/>
* a DVB-S card.<br/>
* a Macintosh G3 (or even G4 or G5 :-) to extend GeeXboX support on this architecture.<br/>
* whatever may inspire you.<br/><br/>

So, if you want to help us, just mail us at <a href="mailto:donate@geexbox.org"><b>donate@geexbox.org</b></a>. And, on behalf of all the developers and users, thank you for your help.<br/>
Here's a description of all of our generous donators, each of them have give us a slight money income to thank us from our work and which will be used to add a better support for hardware stuff into GeeXboX. Many thanks to <use name="donators"/><br/><br/>

Our development team already has received the following piece of hardware. Special thanks to <i><use name="donators-hard"/></i> for their hardware donations.<br/><br/>

<b>Display adapters :</b><br/>
<use name="vboard"/><br/>
<b>Sound cards :</b><br/>
<use name="soundcard"/><br/>
<b>Miscellaneous :</b><br/>
<use name="misc"/><br/>
<b>Complete Systems :</b><br/>
<use name="computer"/>

      </content>
      <content lang="fr" title="Comment puis-je aider ou faire un don ?">
      Faire un don ne signifie pas nécessairement donner de l'argent. Bien entendu, si vous appréciez la GeeXboX et estimez que le temps conscré à la développer mérite une récompense, vos dons monétaires sont les bienvenus (ils seront utilisés dans le sens des requêtes utilisateurs, en vue de meilleures conditions de développement, i.e l'achat de nouveau matériel pour y ajouter son support ...). Si vous souhaitez contribuer financièrement au projet GeeXboX ou tout simplement lui donner un coup de pouce, vous pouvez faire un don via <b>PayPal</b> : c'est à la fois simple et rapide mais surtout, c'est à vous de decider du montant de votre don. A vous de juger la qualité de notre travail. L'ensemble de l'équipe de développement vous en remercie par avance.<br/><br/>

<use name="paypal"/>

Mais vous êtes également en mesure de nous aider de bien différentes manières. Si vous pouvez nous fournir un serveur dédié, de la bande passante, de la publicité, promotion ou encore du matériel spécifique, des pièces informatiques et autres, veuillez nous contacter, votre aide sera toujours la bienvenue. Par ailleurs, vous pouvez également nous aider dans le développement avec vos propres compétences, car nous sommes à la recherche de personnes pour maintenir la documentation et les traductions ainsi que de graphistes.<br/><br/>

A l'heure actuelle, nous avons des besoins particuliers :<br/><br/>
* du matériel informatique (meme vieux) pour y rajouter/améliorer le support (cartes vidéo, cartes son ...).<br/>
* une carte DVB-S (Satellite).<br/>
* un Macintosh G3 (ou mieux G4 ou G5 :-) pour améliorer le support de la GeeXboX pour cette architecture.<br/>
* tout ce qui vous inspire.<br/><br/>

Donc, si vous souhaitez nous aider, envoyez simplement un mail à <a href="mailto:donate@geexbox.org"><b>donate@geexbox.org</b></a>. Et, de la part de tous les développeurs et utilisateurs, merci de tout coeur pour votre aide.<br/>
Vous trouverez ci-dessous la liste de tous les généreux donateurs qui ont contribué financièrement au projet GeeXboX en nous apportant un soutien financier. Chacun d'entre eux à apporter un petit quelque chose qui nous permet de supporter un nombre de composants de plus en plus varié. Un grand merci donc à <use name="donators"/><br/><br/>

Notre équipe de développement à déjà reçu la liste suivante de matériel et autres pièces détachées. Un grand merci à <i><use name="donators-hard"/></i> pour leurs dons de matériel.<br/><br/>

<b>Cartes graphiques :</b><br/>
<use name="vboard"/><br/>
<b>Cartes sons :</b><br/>
<use name="soundcard"/><br/>
<b>Divers : </b><br/>
<use name="misc"/><br/>
<b>Systèmes complets :</b><br/>
<use name="computer"/>

      </content>
      <content lang="de" title="Wie kann ich helfen oder spenden ?">
      Ihre Spenden müssen nicht immer Geldspenden sein. Wenn Sie GeeXboX aber wirklich mögen und der Meinung sind, unsere Zeit für die Entwicklung sollte entsprechend vergütet werden, sind Ihre Geldspenden natürlich sehr willkommen. (Wir verwenden diese, um die gewünschten Verbesserungen der Benutzer zu verwirklichen, indem wir uns bessere Möglichkeiten zur Entwicklung von GeeXboX schaffen, etwa durch den Kauf von neuer Hardware, damit diese dann später unterstützt wird ...). Wenn Sie das GeeXBox Projekt unterstützen möchten, können Sie Ihre Spende mittels <b>PayPal</b> tätigen: Paypal ist einfach in der Handhabung und Sie können damit jeden Betrag spenden. Das gesamte Entwicklerteam bedankt sich hiermit für Ihre Spende!<br/><br/>

<use name="paypal"/>

Sie können uns aber auch auf vielen anderen Wegen helfen. Wenn Sie uns mit dedizierten Servern, Bandbreite, spezieller Hardware und alten Computerteilen aushelfen möchten, setzten Sie sich bitte mit uns in Verbindung.
Natürlich können Sie uns auch mit Werbeartikeln oder durch Werbung unterstützen. Jede Hilfe ist herzlich willkommen. In diesem Zusammenhang können Sie uns auch durch Ihre speziellen Fähigkeiten aushelfen. Wir suchen z.B. nach Leuten, die die Übersetzungen der verschiedenen Sprachen pflegen und ganz speziell nach Designern und Zeichnern.<br/><br/>

Z.Zt. suchen wir gezielt nach folgenden Dingen :<br/><br/>
* Eine Menge an Hardware (auch etwas ältere), um diese in GeeXboX zu unterstützen (Grafikkarten, Soundkarten ...).<br/>
* Eine DVB-S Karte.<br/>
* Einen Macintosh G3 (oder auch G4 oder G5 :-), um die GeeXboX auf dieser Plattform zu verbessern.<br/>
* Alles von dem Sie glauben, das es nützlich wäre.<br/><br/>

Wenn Sie uns also helfen möchten, schreiben Sie einfach an <a href="mailto:donate@geexbox.org"><b>donate@geexbox.org</b></a>. In Vertretung aller Entwickler und Benutzer vielen Dank für Ihre Hilfe.<br/>
Hier ist eine Liste unserer grosszügigen Spender. Jeder von Ihnen hat uns ein kleines Einkommen als Lohn für unsere Arbeit beschert. Wir werden das Geld verwenden, um noch mehr Hardware mit GeeXboX zu unterstützen. Vielen Dank an <use name="donators"/><br/><br/>

Unser Entwicklerteam hat bereits die folgenden Hardwarespenden erhalten. Besonder Dank an <i><use name="donators-hard"/></i> für Ihre Hardwarespenden.<br/><br/>

<b>Grafikkarten :</b><br/>
<use name="vboard"/><br/>
<b>Soundkarten :</b><br/>
<use name="soundcard"/><br/>
<b>Verschiedenes : </b><br/>
<use name="misc"/><br/>
<b>Komplettsysteme :</b><br/>
<use name="computer"/>

      </content>

    </subsection>

  </section>
</article>
