<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<!DOCTYPE article SYSTEM "geexbox.dtd">

<article>
  <define name="response-computing">
    <a href="http://www.responsecomputing.co.uk/html/geexbox.html">Response Computing</a>
  </define>

  <define name="video_supported">
    ATI Rage, ATI RageMobility, ATI Mach64, ATI Rage128, ATI Radeon, ATI X300/600/800, nVidia Riva TnT 1/2, nVidia GeForce 1/2/3/4/5/6 series, 3Dfx Voodoo Banshee, 3Dfx Voodoo 3/4/5, Matrox Mystique/Millenium, Matrox G200/G400/G450/G455/G550/G650/G750, Intel i810/815, Intel i845/855/i865, SiS 300/315/330, Trident Cyberblade, Intel i740, VIA Unichrome.
  </define>
  <define name="video_unsupported">
    VESA 1.2 cards.
  </define>
  <define name="video_untested">
    PowerVR Rendition, Kyro, Kyro II, 3DLabs Permedia2, Matrox Parhelia, NeoMagic.
  </define>

  <define name="audio_pci_supported">
    ALI M5451, ATI IXP 150/200/250/300, Aureal Advantage, Aurel Vortex 1/2, Aztech AZF3328/PCI168, Cirrus Logic Sound Fusion CS4280/CS461x/CS462x/CS463x/CS4281, SoundBlaster EMU10K1 (SB512, Live, Audigy, E-mu APS), SoundBlaster EMU10K1X (SB Live! 24 bits, SB Audigy LS), NeoMagic NM256AV/ZX, Trident 4D-Wave, SiS 7018, Yamaha YMF724/740/744/754, Advance Logic ALS4000, C-Media 8738, 8338, Ensoniq AudioPCI 1370/1371/1373 (SB64/128), ESS ES1938/1946/1961 (Solo-1), ESS ES1968/1978 (Maestro-1/2/2E), ESS Allegro/Maestro3, ForteMedia FM801, ICEnsemble ICE1712 (Envy24), ICE/VT1724/1720 (Envy24HT/PT), Intel i8x0/MX440, SiS 7012/7013, ALI 5455, nForce Audio, AMD 768/8111, S3 SonicVibes, VIA 82C686A/B, Digigram VX222, Intel High Definition Audio (Azalia)
  </define>
  <define name="audio_isa_supported">
    Analog Devices AD18616A/AD1848, Cirrus Logic CS4248/CS423{1|2|6+}, ESS ES968/688/1688/18xx, Gravis UltraSound Classic/Extreme/MAX, AMD InterWave, OPTi 82C92x/93x, SoundBlaster 1.0/2.0/Pro, Sound Blaster 16, Sound Blaster AWE32/64, Turle Beach Maui/Tropez(+), Advance Logic ALS100/120, Aztech AZT2320, C-Media CMI8330, Diamond DT-019X, Advance Logic ALS-007, Yamaha OPL3-SA2/SA3, Aztech Sound Galaxy, Ensoniq SoundScape.
  </define>
  <define name="audio_unsupported">
    Korg 1212, Digigram miXart, RME Digi32/96/9652, RME Hammerfall, PCMCIA cards, USB devices.
  </define>

  <define name="accel_supported">
    RealMagic Hollywood+, Creative DXR3 (EM8300 chipset).
  </define>
  <define name="accel_unsupported">
    Creative DXR2, RealMagic Xcard (EM8500 chipset).
  </define>

  <define name="ata_supported">
    CMD64{0|3|6|8|9}, OPTi 82C621, RZ1000, AEC62XX, ALI M15x3, AMD-7xx, AMD-8111, nVidia nForce, ATI IXP, CY82C693, Cyrix CS5530 MediaGX, HighPoint HPT34X/36X/37X, Intel PIIXn, NS87415, Promise PDC202{46|62|65|67|68|69|70|71|75|76|77}, Silicon Image, SiS 55xx/56xx/5xx/6xx/7xx, , SLC90E66, VIA82CXX.
  </define>
  <define name="ata_unsupported">
    Compaq Triflex, Cyrix CS5510/20 MediaGX, National SCx200, ServerWorks OSB4/CSB5/CSB6, Tekram TRM290.
  </define>

  <define name="sata_supported">
    Promise SX8, ServerWorks Frodo, Apple K2, Intel PIIX/ICH, nVidia, Promise TX2/TX4, Promise SX4, Silicon Image, SiS 964/180, VIA, VITESSE VASC-7174, QStor.
  </define>
  <define name="sata_unsupported">
    None.
  </define>

  <define name="scsi_supported">
    Tekram DC390(T), Am53/79C974, SYM53C8xx, Adaptec AIC7xx Fast.
  </define>
  <define name="scsi_unsupported">
    All other controllers.
  </define>

  <define name="eth_supported">
    3COM 3c50x (EtherLink serie), 3COM 3c590/900/990 series (Vortex/Boomerang/Typhoon), WD/SMC Ultra ISA, AMD PCnet32, AMD 8111, Adaptec Starfire/DuraLAN, Broadcom 4400, nForce, Intel EtherExpress Pro, National Semiconductor DP8381x, NE2000 PCI, RealTek 8139(C+), RealTek 8129/8130, SiS 900/7016, SMC EtherPower, VIA Rhine, VIA Velocity (Giga), Alteon AceNIC/3Com 3C958 (Giga), NetGear GA620 (Giga), Intel Pro 1000, RealTek 8169 (Giga), Marvell Yukon (Giga), SysKonnect SK-98xx (Giga), Broadcom Tigon3 (Giga), Tulip.
  </define>
  <define name="eth_unsupported">
    3COM 3c525 ISA, AMD Lance ISA, SMC 9194, ATxxx, DExxx, HPxxx, other ISA cards, D-Link DL2000 (Giga), National Semiconductor DP83820. All PCMCIA cards.
  </define>
 
  <define name="link-wifi">
    <a href="http://www.hpl.hp.com/personal/Jean_Tourrilhes/Linux/Wireless.html">Jean Tourrilhes' Page</a>
  </define>
  <define name="wifi_supported">
    Hermes (Orinoco), Intersil HFA384x (Prism 2), Prism 2.5, Ralinktech RT2400, Ralinktech RT2500, Cisco 34X, Cisco 35X, Aironet 4500, Aironet 4800(B), Atmel at76c50x, Intel Centrino IPW2100/IPW2200, Prism54/GT.
  </define>
  <define name="wifi_unsupported">
    Texas Instruments ACX100, RealTek 8180, Admteck ADM 8211, Atheros, USB Prism3, PCMCIA cards.
  </define>

  <define name="tv_supported">
    BrookTree BT848/BT878, Philips SAA7134, Conexant 2388x.
  </define>

  <define name="dvb_supported">
    All devices based on BT8x8, SAA7136 (a.k.a AV7110) and CX88 chipsets like : Fujitsu-Siemens, Galaxis PCTV-SAT, Technisat SkyStar 1, Hauppauge WinTV Nexus-s, Hauppauge WinTV NOVA-s, Technotrend PCline budget DVB-S, Technisat Skystar 2, Hercules Smart TV Satellite, DVICO FusionHDTV DVB-S, Technotrend TT-DVB-T 1200, Technotrend TT-DVB-T 1500, Technotrend TT-DVB-T 1300, Lorenzen SL DVB-T PCI, Hauppauge WinTV-NOVA-T PCI, Technotrend TT-PCline Budget3 TA1000, AVerMedia AverTV DVB-T 761 PCI, AVerMedia AverTV DVB-T 771 PCI, Technisat Airstar2/Air2PC DVB, TwinHan VisionDTV Ter PCI, Hama DVB-T PCI-Karte, K-World V-Stream Xpert DVB-T PCI, ChainTech DTT 1000 PCI, Nebula DigiTV PCI, Satelco PCI, Pinnacle PCTV MediaCenter 300i, Terratec Cinergy 1200 DVB-T, Terratec Cinergy 1400 DVB-T, LifeView, FlyDVB-T Duo, LifeView FlyDVB-T, GDI Black Gold, Technotrend DVB-C 1.0 Budget, Twinhan VisionDTV Mini Cab DVB-C, Terratec Cinergy 1200 DVB-C PCI, Fujitsu-Siemens DVB-C PCI, Technotrend PCLine Premium DVB-C Rev. 2.1 (C2100), Technotrend Premium DVB-C 2300 OT, Hauppauge WinTV DVB-C Rev. 2.1, Hauppauge WinTV-Nexus-CA, AVerMedia AverTV A800, DiBcom USB1.1 DVB-T devices (based on the DiB3000M-B), DiBcom USB2.0 DVB-T devices (based on the DiB3000M-C/P), HanfTek UMT-010, Hauppauge WinTV-NOVA-T USB2, Nebula DigiTV USB version - DVB-T, TerraTec Cinergy T², Twinhan DVB-T USB2.0, WideView/Yakumo/Hama/Typhoon/Yuan Boxes and Pens, TwinhanDTV StarBox - DVB-S.
  </define>

  <define name="fs_supported">
    EXT2/3, ReseirFS, ISO9660, Joliet, UDF, VFAT, NTFS (RO), xBSD UFS (RO), NFS, Samba SMB, CIFS
  </define>
  <define name="fs_unsupported">
    JFS, XFS, Minix, ROMfs, NTFS (RW), ADFS, Amiga FFS, Apple HFS, BeOS BeFS, BFS, EFS, Comrpessed ROM CramFS, FreeVxFS, OS/2 HPFS, QNX4 FS, xBSD UFS (RW), NFS 3/4, NCP, AFS.
  </define>

  <define name="misc_supported">
    USB Joysticks, XboX GamePad, Cards readers, ATI Remote Wonder, Radio adapters.
  </define>
  <define name="misc_unsupported">
    Mouse, RAID controllers, PCMCIA cards.
  </define>

  <define name="linuxtv-wiki">
    <a href="http://linuxtv.org/wiki/index.php/Main_Page">LinuxTV Wiki</a>
  </define>

  <section label="hard">
    <content lang="en" title="Supported Hardware ..."/>
    <content lang="fr" title="Matériel compatible ..."/>
    <content lang="de" title="Kompatible Hardware ..."/>
    <subsection label="hard_rc">
      <content lang="en" title="Get an officially supported computer ...">
        Of course GeeXboX should work on any kind of computer but you may want to buy a new one that is officially supported by our development team. <use name="response-computing"/> is a UK computer shop that sells hardware that has been approved by GeeXboX team to be fully compliant. It looks like an embedded mini-itx platform, featuring an EPIA-MII motherboard, and shipped with a pre-installed version of GeeXboX. Then, if you look for an easy way to build a GeeXboX, you may be interested by <use name="response-computing"/>. Moreover, 5£ are given back to our development team for each computer sold.
      </content>
      <content lang="fr" title="Se procurer un ordinateur officiellement supporté ...">
        Bien entendu, la GeeXboX a été conçue pour fonctionner sur tout type d'ordinateur, mais vous pouvez vouloir en acheter un, dédié à devenir platine de salon, et qui soit certifié par l'équipe de développement. <use name="response-computing"/> est une société anglaise qui commercialise un système embarqué qui a été officiellment testé et certifié par notre équipe de développement. Il s'agit d'une plateforme Mini-ITX, basée sur une carte mère EPIA-MII, et qui est vendue avec une version pré-installée de la GeeXboX. Ainsi, si vous cherchez un moyen facile de construire votre propre GeeXboX, vous pourrez être intéressés par l'offre de <use name="response-computing"/>. De plus, 5£ sont reversées à l'équipe de développement pour chaque vente.
      </content>
      <content lang="de" title="Erwerben Sie einen offiziell unterstützten Computer ...">
        GeeXboX sollte eigentlich mit jedem Computer funktionieren. Wenn Sie aber vielleicht trotzdem einen neuen Computer erwerben möchten, dann vielleicht einen, der offiziell vom GeeXboX Team zertifiziert ist. <use name="response-computing"/> ist ein in England ansässiger Computerversand, der vom GeeXboX Team auf Kompatibilität geprüfte Hardware versendet. Die Plattformbasis bildet ein mini ITX Motherboard, (EPIA-MII) und das vollständige System wird mit vorinstallierter GeeXboX ausgeliefert. Wenn Sie also nach einer Möglichkeit suchen, möglichst einfach eine GeeXboX zu basteln, kann Ihnen <use name="response-computing"/> bestimmt weiterhelfen. Zusätzlich erhält das Entwicklerteam eine 5 Pfund Gutschrift für jeden verkauften Computer.
      </content>
    </subsection>

    <subsection label="list_hard">
      <content lang="en" title="List of supported hardware ...">
GeeXboX has been designed to work on almost every kind of computer, being as generic as possible. Thus, most of the components of your computer are supported. Whatever the brand or model of your motherboard, CD/DVD drive, hard disk, CPU and memory, GeeXboX will be able to recognize and use it well. The only real requirement in fact is to have a PC (x86 architecture) or Macintosh (PowerPC architecture).<br/><br/>

Mainly for technical reasons, not all of the extended components are supported (but most of them are). The list above will try to describe for each kind of peripheral, which one is supported and which aren't.<br/><br/>

Unsupported hardware may be due to several reasons. For some of them, the reason is quite simple : there's no free and open-source drivers working under Linux. Please do not complain to us that your hardware is not supported in this case, you were the one who bought hardware which is Windows only compliant. For other pieces of hardware, adding support to GeeXboX is simply not trivial and even if it's possible, our development team do not have the required hardware to test it. To conclude, please notice that hardware described as supported may not have been tested. Even if most of the supported hardware has been validated by the GeeXboX team, some is remained untested as we do not own it. So, consider the above list as a theoretical support list, nothing's more.<br/><br/>

And one last thing, many components are described by the name of the chipset they are using. We really do not know which brand or model is using which kind of chipset and honnestly we do not care about. If some manufacturer do not provide you this information (which is quite essential), complain about him not us.<br/>
      </content>
      <content lang="fr" title="Liste de matériel compatible ...">
La GeeXboX a été conçue pour fonctionner sur presque n'importe quel type d'ordinateur, essayant de rester aussi générique que possible. De ce fait, la plupart des composants de vore ordinateur sont supportés. Quelle que soit la marque ou le modèle de votre carte mère, de votre lecteur CD/DVD, disque dur, processeur et mémoire, ils sont reconnus et la GeeXboX est en mesure de les utiliser pleinement. La seule véritable contrainte au final, est de disposer d'un PC (architecture x86) ou d'un Macintosh (architecture PowerPC).<br/><br/>

Pour des raisons essentiellement techniques, tous les composants additionnels ne sont par contre pas compatibles ou supportés (bien que la majorité le soit). La liste ci-dessous a été faite dans le but de décrire dans la mesure du possible, pour chaque type de périphérique, ceux qui sont supportés et ceux qui ne le sont pas.<br/><br/>

Le fait que votre matériel ne soit pas supporté par la GeeXboX peut avoir plusieurs raisons. Pour certains composants, la raison est fort simple : il n'existe pas de drivers libre et open-source fonctionnant avec Linux. Veuillez dans ce cas, ne pas vous plaindre du non-support de votre matériel, vous n'aviez qu'à ne pas acheter du matériel conçu exclusivement pour Microsoft Windows. Pour d'autres périphériques dont les drivers existent, ajouter leur support à la GeeXboX n'est simplement pas trivial et s'il est possible de le faire, notre équipe n'a simplement pas en sa possession le matériel, ce qui empêche tout test et toute inclusion. Pour finir, veuillez noter que le matériel décrit ci-dessous comme supporté peut ne pas avoir été testé. Bien que la plupart du matériel dit compatible ait été testé et validé par notre équipe de développement, certaines pièces n'ont jamais pu être testées car nous n'en disposons pas. Veuillez donc considérer cette liste comme une liste de support théorique, et rien de plus.<br/><br/>

Et, dernière chose, la plupart des composants sont décrits par le nom du chipset qu'ils intégrent. Nous ne connaissons absolument pas les marques ou modèles qui inclut chacun de ces chipsets et en toute honnêteté, ce n'est pas notre problème. Si un constructeur n'est pas en mesure de vous fournir une information aussi simple (et pourtant tellement essentielle), c'est chez lui que vous pourrez vous en plaindre, mais pas ici.<br/>
      </content>
      <content lang="de" title="Hardware - Kompatibilitätsliste ...">
GeeXboX wurde unter dem Gesichtspunkt entwickelt, auf möglichst jedem Computersystem zu funktionieren. Daher werden sicher die meisten Ihrer Hardware-Komponenten unterstützt. Dabei spielt es keine Rolle, wer der Hersteller Ihres Motherboards, des CD/DVD-Laufwerkes, der Festplatte, CPU oder Speichers ist. GeeXboX wird all Ihre Hardware erkennen und in der Lage sein, diese auch vernünftig zu nutzen. Einzige Grundvoraussetzung ist ein PC (x86) oder ein PowerPC  Macintosh (PPC).<br/><br/>

Aus technischen Gründen werden nicht alle Erweiterungskarten richtig unterstützt (aber die meisten werden es). Die folgende Liste gibt für jeden Peripherietyp an, welcher unterstützt wird und welche nicht.  

Hardware kann aus den verschiedensten Gründen inkompatibel mit GeeXboX sein. Bei einiger Hardware ist der Grund dafür sehr einfach : Es gibt keinen freien Open-Source Treiber, der mit Linux funktioniert. Beschweren Sie sich also bitte nicht bei uns, wenn Ihre gekaufte Hardware nur zu Windows kompatibel ist und nicht mit GeeXboX funktioniert.
Für nicht unterstütze Hardware ist es nämlich sehr sehr schwierig, Unterstützung in GeeXboX zu implementieren, wenn nicht sogar völlig unmöglich. Ausserdem besitzt unser Entwicklerteam meist nicht die erwähnte Hardware und ist daher gar nicht in der Lage, diese zu testen. Die meiste, der als kompatibel gelisteten Hardware, wurde auch vom Team selbst geprüft. Dennoch ist diese Liste mehr "theoretischer" Natur, da wir nicht all die gelistete Hardware besitzen, um diese auch selbst zu testen.

Noch ein Hinweis zum Schluss. Viele der hier gelisteten Hardware wurde nach dem Chipsatz aufgeführt, den sie verwenden, nicht nach Herstellernamen. Wir wissen daher, nicht welches Modell welchen Chipsatz benutzt und das ist auch zum Glück unwichtig, da nur der Chipsatz für uns von Interesse ist. Wenn Ihnen einige Hersteller keine Angaben über den verwendeten Chipsatz der Hardware macht (was zu Wissen aber sehr wichtig ist), fragen Sie bitte den Hersteller, nicht uns.
.<br/>
      </content>
    </subsection>

    <subsection label="hard_video">
      <content lang="en" title="Video Adapters ...">
      - <b>Supported cards</b> : VESA 2.0 compliant cards like <use name="video_supported"/><br/><br/>
      - <b>Unsupported cards</b> : <use name="video_unsupported"/><br/><br/>
      - <b>Untested cards (may work)</b> : <use name="video_untested"/><br/>
      </content>
      <content lang="fr" title="Cartes graphiques ...">
      - <b>Cartes supportées</b> : Toutes les cartes compatible avec la norme VESA 2.0 comme par exemple les <use name="video_supported"/><br/><br/>
      - <b>Cartes non supportées</b> : <use name="video_unsupported"/><br/><br/>
      - <b>Cartes non testées (mais qui peuvent fonctionner)</b> : <use name="video_untested"/><br/>
      </content>
      <content lang="de" title="Grafikkarten ...">
      - <b>Unterstützte Karten</b> : VESA 2.0 kompatible Karten wie <use name="video_supported"/><br/><br/>
      - <b>Nicht unterstützte Karten</b> : <use name="video_unsupported"/><br/><br/>
      - <b>Ungetestet Karten (können funktionieren)</b> : <use name="video_untested"/><br/>
      </content>
    </subsection>

    <subsection label="hard_audio">
      <content lang="en" title="Sound Cards ...">
      - <b>Supported PCI cards</b> : <use name="audio_pci_supported"/><br/><br/>
      - <b>Supported ISA cards</b> : <use name="audio_isa_supported"/><br/><br/>
      - <b>Unsupported cards</b> : <use name="audio_unsupported"/><br/>
      </content>
      <content lang="fr" title="Cartes Son ...">
      - <b>Cartes PCI supportées</b> : <use name="audio_pci_supported"/><br/><br/>
      - <b>Cartes ISA supportées</b> : <use name="audio_isa_supported"/><br/><br/>
      - <b>Cartes non supportées</b> : <use name="audio_unsupported"/><br/>
      </content>
      <content lang="de" title="Soundkarten ...">
      - <b>Unterstützte PCI Karten</b> : <use name="audio_pci_supported"/><br/><br/>
      - <b>Unterstützte ISA Karten</b> : <use name="audio_isa_supported"/><br/><br/>
      - <b>Nicht unterstützte Karten</b> : <use name="audio_unsupported"/><br/>
      </content>
    </subsection>

    <subsection label="hard_accel">
      <content lang="en" title="Hardware Acceleration Cards ...">
      - <b>Supported cards</b> : <use name="accel_supported"/><br/><br/>
      - <b>Unsupported cards</b> : <use name="accel_unsupported"/><br/>
      </content>
      <content lang="fr" title="Cartes d'accélération matérielle ...">
      - <b>Cartes supportées</b> : <use name="accel_supported"/><br/><br/>
      - <b>Cartes non supportées</b> : <use name="accel_unsupported"/><br/>
      </content>
      <content lang="de" title="Hardwarebeschleunigte Karten ...">
      - <b>Unterstützte Karten</b> : <use name="accel_supported"/><br/><br/>
      - <b>Nicht unterstützte Karten</b> : <use name="accel_unsupported"/><br/>
      </content>
    </subsection>

    <subsection label="hard_ata">
      <content lang="en" title="ATA Controllers ...">
      - <b>Supported controllers</b> : <use name="ata_supported"/><br/><br/>
      - <b>Unsupported controllers</b> : <use name="ata_unsupported"/><br/>
      </content>
      <content lang="fr" title="Controlleurs ATA ...">
      - <b>Controlleurs supportés</b> : <use name="ata_supported"/><br/><br/>
      - <b>Controlleurs non supportés</b> : <use name="ata_unsupported"/><br/>
      </content>
      <content lang="de" title="ATA Controller ...">
      - <b>Unterstützte Controller</b> : <use name="ata_supported"/><br/><br/>
      - <b>Nicht unterstützte Controller</b> : <use name="ata_unsupported"/><br/>
      </content>
    </subsection>

    <subsection label="hard_sata">
      <content lang="en" title="Serial-ATA Controllers ...">
      - <b>Supported controllers</b> : <use name="sata_supported"/><br/><br/>
      - <b>Unsupported controllers</b> : <use name="sata_unsupported"/><br/>
      </content>
      <content lang="fr" title="Controlleurs Serial-ATA ...">
      - <b>Controlleurs supportés</b> : <use name="sata_supported"/><br/><br/>
      - <b>Controlleurs non supportés</b> : <use name="sata_unsupported"/><br/>
      </content>
      <content lang="de" title="Serial-ATA Controller ...">
      - <b>Unterstützte Controller</b> : <use name="sata_supported"/><br/><br/>
      - <b>Nicht unterstützte Controller</b> : <use name="sata_unsupported"/><br/>
      </content>
    </subsection>

    <subsection label="hard_scsi">
      <content lang="en" title="SCSI Controllers ...">
      - <b>Supported controllers</b> : <use name="scsi_supported"/><br/><br/>
      - <b>Unsupported controllers</b> : <use name="scsi_unsupported"/><br/>
      </content>
      <content lang="fr" title="Controlleurs SCSI ...">
      - <b>Controlleurs supportés</b> : <use name="scsi_supported"/><br/><br/>
      - <b>Controlleurs non supportés</b> : <use name="scsi_unsupported"/><br/>
      </content>
      <content lang="de" title="SCSI Controller ...">
      - <b>Unterstützte Controller</b> : <use name="scsi_supported"/><br/><br/>
      - <b>Nicht unterstützte Controller</b> : <use name="scsi_unsupported"/><br/>
      </content>
    </subsection>

    <subsection label="hard_ethernet">
      <content lang="en" title="Ethernet Cards (10/100/1000) ...">
      - <b>Supported chipsets</b> : <use name="eth_supported"/><br/><br/>
      - <b>Unsupported chipsets</b> : <use name="eth_unsupported"/><br/>
      </content>
      <content lang="fr" title="Cartes Ethernet (10/100/1000) ...">
      - <b>Chipsets supportés</b> : <use name="eth_supported"/><br/><br/>
      - <b>Chipsets non supportés</b> : <use name="eth_unsupported"/><br/>
      </content>
      <content lang="de" title="Netzwerkarten (10/100/1000) ...">
      - <b>Unterstützte Chipsätze</b> : <use name="eth_supported"/><br/><br/>
      - <b>Nicht unterstützte Chipsätze</b> : <use name="eth_unsupported"/><br/>
      </content>
    </subsection>

    <subsection label="hard_wifi">
      <content lang="en" title="WiFi Cards (802.11b/g) ...">
      - <b>Supported chipsets</b> : <use name="wifi_supported"/><br/><br/>
      - <b>Unsupported chipsets</b> : <use name="wifi_unsupported"/><br/><br/>
      More details and specifications about wireless chipsets, cards and manufacturers can be found at <use name="link-wifi"/>
      </content>
      <content lang="fr" title="Cartes WiFi (802.11b/g) ...">
      - <b>Chipsets supportés</b> : <use name="wifi_supported"/><br/><br/>
      - <b>Chipsets non supportés</b> : <use name="wifi_unsupported"/><br/><br/>
      De plus amples détails et spécifications sur les chipsets WiFi, les cartes et les fabricants peuvent être trouvé sur la <use name="link-wifi"/>
      </content>
      <content lang="de" title="WiFi Karten (802.11b/g) ...">
      - <b>Unterstützte Chipsätze</b> : <use name="wifi_supported"/><br/><br/>
      - <b>Nicht unterstützte Chipsätze</b> : <use name="wifi_unsupported"/><br/><br/>
      Mehr Informationen über Wireless Chipsätze, Karten und Hersteller finden Sie unter <use name="link-wifi"/>
      </content>
    </subsection>

    <subsection label="hard_tv">
      <content lang="en" title="TV Cards ...">
      - <b>Supported chipsets</b> : <use name="tv_supported"/><br/><br/>
      </content>
      <content lang="fr" title="Cartes TV ...">
      - <b>Chipsets supportés</b> : <use name="tv_supported"/><br/><br/>
      </content>
      <content lang="de" title="TV - Karten ...">
      - <b>Unterstützte Chipsätze</b> : <use name="tv_supported"/><br/><br/>
      </content>
    </subsection>

    <subsection label="hard_dvb">
      <content lang="en" title="DVB Cards ...">
      - <b>Supported chipsets</b> : <use name="dvb_supported"/><br/>
        <br/>
        Always check on <use name="linuxtv-wiki"/> for precise card support.<br/>
      </content>
      <content lang="fr" title="Cartes DVB ...">
      - <b>Chipsets supportés</b> : <use name="dvb_supported"/><br/>
        <br/>
        Vérifiez toujours sur le <use name="linuxtv-wiki"/> pour un support précis.<br/>
      </content>
      <content lang="de" title="DVB - Karten ...">
      - <b>Unterstützte Chipsätze</b> : <use name="dvb_supported"/><br/><br/>
      </content>
    </subsection>

    <subsection label="hard_fs">
      <content lang="en" title="FileSystems ...">
      - <b>Supported file systems</b> : <use name="fs_supported"/><br/><br/>
      - <b>Unsupported file systems</b> : <use name="fs_unsupported"/><br/>
      </content>
      <content lang="fr" title="Systèmes de fichiers ...">
      - <b>Systèmes de fichiers supportés</b> : <use name="fs_supported"/><br/><br/>
      - <b>Systèmes de fichiers non supportés</b> : <use name="fs_unsupported"/><br/>
      </content>
      <content lang="de" title="Dateisysteme ...">
      - <b>Unterstützte Dateisysteme</b> : <use name="fs_supported"/><br/><br/>
      - <b>Nicht unterstützte Dateisysteme</b> : <use name="fs_unsupported"/><br/>
      </content>
    </subsection>

    <subsection label="hard_misc">
      <content lang="en" title="Miscellaneous ...">
      - <b>Supported devices</b> : <use name="misc_supported"/><br/><br/>
      - <b>Unsupported devices</b> : <use name="misc_unsupported"/><br/>
      </content>
      <content lang="fr" title="Périphériques divers ...">
      - <b>Périphériques supportés</b> : <use name="misc_supported"/><br/><br/>
      - <b>Périphériques non supportés</b> : <use name="misc_unsupported"/><br/>
      </content>
      <content lang="de" title="Verschiedenes ...">
      - <b>Unterstützte Geräte</b> : <use name="misc_supported"/><br/><br/>
      - <b>Nicht unterstützte Geräte</b> : <use name="misc_unsupported"/><br/>
      </content>
    </subsection>
  </section>
</article>
