<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE article [
<!ENTITY % geexboxent  SYSTEM "geexbox.dtd">
%geexboxent;
<!ENTITY % HTMLlat1 PUBLIC
	 "-//W3C//ENTITIES Latin 1 for XHTML//EN"
	 "http://www.w3.org/TR/xhtml1/DTD/xhtml-lat1.ent">
%HTMLlat1;
]>

<article>

  <section label="news">
    <content lang="en" title="Latest News ..."/>
    <content lang="fr" title="Dernières Nouvelles ..."/>
    <content lang="de" title="Aktuelle Nachrichten ..."/>

    <subsection label="what_is_geexbox">
      <content lang="en" title="What is GeeXboX ?">
        GeeXboX is a free embedded Linux distribution which aims at
        turning your computer into a so called HTPC (Home Theater PC)
        or Media Center. Being a standalone LiveCD-based distribution,
        it's a ready to boot operating system than works on any
        Pentium-class x86 computer or PowerPC Macintosh, implying no software
        requirement. You can even use it on a diskless computer, the
        whole system being loaded in RAM.
        <br/><br/>
        Despite his tiny ISO image size, the distribution comes with a
        complete and automatic hardware detection, not requiring any
        driver to be added. It supports playback of nearly any kind of
        audio/video and image files and all known codecs and
        containers are shipped in, allowing playing them through
        various physical supports, either being CD, DVD, HDD, LAN or
        Internet.
        <br/><br/>
        GeeXboX also comes with a complete toolchain that allows
        developers adding easily extra packages and features but that
        might also be used to give birth to many dedicated embedded
        Linux systems.
      </content>
      <content lang="fr" title="Qu'est ce que la GeeXboX ?">
        La GeeXboX est une distribution Linux libre et à caractère
        embarqué qui se propose de transformer votre ordinateur en ce
        que l'on nomme désormais un HTPC (Home Theater PC) ou encore
        Media Center. Etant distribuée sous la forme d'un CD
        auto-amorçable, il s'agit d'un système d'exploitation prêt à
        l'emploi, capable de fonctionner sur tout type de PC de classe
        Pentium et supérieure ou encore de Macintosh à base de
        PowerPC, le tout ne nécessitant aucun autre logiciel. Il vous
        sera également possible de l'utiliser sur un ordinateur
        dépourvu de disque dur, le système étant intégralement chargé
        en mémoire.
        <br/><br/>
        En dépit de la très petite taille de son image ISO, la
        distribution propose une reconnaissance complète et
        automatisée de votre configuration matérielle, ne nécessitant
        donc l'ajout d'aucun pilote de périphérique particulier. Le
        système supporte la lecture de la quasi totalité des formats
        audio/vidéo ou d'images existants et, l'ensemble des codecs et
        containeurs multimédias connus y sont intégrés. Il est
        également possible de lire vos contenus depuis des sources
        très variées comme par exemple un CD, un DVD, votre (vos)
        disque(s) dur(s) (locaux ou distants), votre réseau local ou
        encore directement depuis Internet.
        <br/><br/>
        La GeeXboX est également accompagnée d'une chaîne de
        cross-compilation complète, permettant aux développeurs de
        très facilement étendre ses fonctionnalités, d'y ajouter des
        paquetages, ou encore de le réutiliser pour donner naissance à
        de nouveaux systèmes Linux embarqués dédiés.
      </content>
    </subsection>

    <subsection label="geexbox_1.1" date="2007-00-00">
      <content lang="en" title="GeeXboX 1.1 : CODENAME">
        Although development never stopped, more than a year has passed
        without any new official GeeXboX release. This new one is a really
        good candidate for your HTPC multimedia distribution choice. It comes
        with an improved hardware support, providing dozens of new drivers
        (new VIDIX stack for video playback, a lot of new WiFi controllers,
        DVB card chipsets and new remote controls). It also comes with a
        massively upgraded and more stable MPlayer, which features
        native decoding of various audio/video formats/codecs that used to be
        available through non-free Win32 DLLs only (such as Windows Media
        Video, Flash ...). Also, GeeXboX now has some decoding speed
        improvements (use of SSSE3 instructions from Core2Duos has been added)
        and the OSD menu has been completely rewritten to provide a lot of new
        attractives features. Oh, and did we mention ? It can plays decrypted
        EVO files from HD-DVD ?<br/>
        <br/>
        While still working on version 2.0, the next version of GeeXboX (1.2)
        will come with some features that were requested for quite a long time.
        First, it'll come in both 32 and 64 bits editions (second one is 15%
        faster). But more importantly, it'll be first version of GeeXboX
        to come with a native HDTV screens support. So, just stay tuned, most
        of these features are already available, and 1.2 won't take a year
        to come this time ;-) By the way, speaking about the future, we're
        looking for a Sony PlayStation 3 to port GeeXboX to: that would make
        the best HTPC ever. Feel free to help us doing so ;-)<br/>
        <br/>
        But let's get back to 1.1 release and just enjoy using it.<br/>
        <br/>
        <b>Detailed Changelog (relative to 1.0 release) :</b><br/>
        <br/>
        <b>System:</b><br/>
        - Update Linux to v2.6.21.3<br/>
        - Upgrade BusyBox to v1.5.1<br/>
        - Update uClibc to 0.9.29.<br/>
        - Upgraded SysLinux bootloader to v3.20.<br/>
        - Better CPU frequency scaling capabilities.<br/>
        <br/>
        <b>Toolchain:</b><br/>
        - Added optional support for GNU glibc 2.5 in toolchain for debugging
        purpose.<br/>
        - Upgrade to GCC 4.1.2<br/>
        <br/>
        <b>Player:</b><br/>
        - Upgrade to MPlayer SVN v23418.<br/>
        - Added support libavformat demuxer in addition to internal
        libmpdemux.<br/>
        - New native VC-1/WMV3/WMV9 video decoder (Windows Media Video).<br/>
        - New native On2 VP50 and VP62 decoder (Flash video).<br/>
        - New native lossless audio decoders for WavPack, TTA, and
        Shorten.<br/>
        - Support for VC1 in MPEG-TS and MPEG-PS files (like HD-DVD and
        BlueRay ones).<br/>
        - Support for EVO demuxing (HD-DVD file format).<br/>
        - Added support for VP7 binary codec.<br/>
        - Added binary extra codec (through Generator) for WMA Pro files
        handling.<br/>
        - Added binary codec for VC-1 codec as the native decoder is not (yet)
        able to decode all samples.<br/>
        - Support for audio stream switching in MPEG-TS/PS, Matroska and
        streams supported by libavformat.<br/>
        - Support for audio stream switching between streams with different
        codecs.<br/>
        - New native RTSP input (handles MPEG-TS over RTP only) for generic
        RTSP servers (like FreeboxTV) which deprecates Live555 usage.<br/>
        - Fixed A/V synchronization issues with FreeboxTV.<br/>
        - H.264 decoding speed improvements.<br/>
        - SSA/ASS subtitle renderer.<br/>
        - Added support for ICEcast netstreams.<br/>
        - Radio is now handled direclty through V4L2.<br/>
        - Support for 3GP, AAC, VDR and DVR-MS files.<br/>
        - Added a new <i>Preferences</i> menu, with many new options to
        control audio streams, subtitles, colors and tweak all video
        parameters.<br/>
        - Removed libdts, libmpcdec, libogg, libvorbis and libtheora, as
        deprecated by new MPlayer internal decoders/demuxers.<br/>
        - Allows loading external subtitle files.<br/>
        - Allows setting playback speed.<br/>
        - Allow selection of radio Genres, and store each genre in a subfolder
        for easier discovery.<br/>
        <br/>
        <b>Video:</b><br/>
        - Added new VIDIX drivers stack, adding support for ATI Radeons R350
        (Radeon 9600) to R520 (Radeon X1900).<br/>
        - Fix with VESA on i945 cards.<br/>
        <br/>
        <b>Drivers:</b><br/>
        - Added support for IVTV based cards (such as Hauppauge PVR
        150/250/350/500).<br/>
        - Support for WPA encryption on WiFi cards.<br/>
        - Added support for Broadcom BCM43xx WiFi chipsets (like Apple
        AirPort).<br/>
        - Added Ralink RT61 and RT73 chipsets support.<br/>
        - Added support for wireless TI ACX111 chipsets.<br/>
        - Added support for MadWiFi-NG driver.<br/>
        - Added support for ZyDAS ZD12x1 wireless chipsets.<br/>
        - Added support for PVR USB 2 TV card.<br/>
        - Added support for Rio Karma USB mass storage devices.<br/>
        - Added support for USB soundcards.<br/>
        - Fixed ATI USB mouse directional keycodes.<br/>
        - Added Medion (also Aldi) X-10 OEM'd remote.<br/>
        - Added support for Logitech UltraX Media remote.<br/>
        - Added support for some USB to serial interfaces.<br/>
        - Introduced new libata support in kernel for IDE disks support.<br/>
        - Do no more force disks to 32bits I/O (crashes with CompactFlash
        over IDE).<br/>
        - Much better autodetection of USB DVB devices.<br/>
        - Support for more radio cards.<br/>
        - Rework of DVB firmware loader.<br/>
        <br/>
        <b>Networking:</b><br/>
        - Support for IPv4 multicast (useful for RTSP streams).<br/>
        - Added NdisWrapper support that allows using Win32 network (WiFi)
        drivers under Linux.<br/>
        - Upgraded bftpd to version 1.8.4 and added new file /etc/ftp for
        FTP authentication.<br/>
        - Updated Samba to 3.0.25, uses UTF-8 charset to mount shares and
        fixes some mount points handling issues.<br/>
        - Allows Samba and NFS mounts to come up if the servers are brought
        up after geexbox boots up, by looping in the background.<br/>
        - Added basic WebGUI implementation.<br/>
        <br/>
        <b>Generator:</b><br/>
        - Support for NDISwrapper driver loading.<br/>
        - Added new tab to add extra files to generated ISO image.<br/>
        - New generator option to set WiFi channel number.<br/>
        - Support for Windows Vista.<br/>
        <br/>
        <b>Miscellaneous:</b><br/>
        - Removed deprecated non-working recorder/mencoder support.<br/>
        - Added remote=/receiver= cheat codes in isolinux for easy
        change.<br/>
        - Added menus in installator for selecting remote/receivers.<br/>
        - Added support for various keyboard mapping
        (azerty/qwerty/qwertz)<br/>
        - New makefile rules to build and play VMware virtual machines
        (make vmx; make vmx-play).<br/>
        - Fixed QEMU/VirtualBox emulation.<br/>
        - Add autoplay support for USB devices.<br/>
        - Reworked internationalization files.<br/>
        - Support for multiple languages in the same ISO image.<br/>
        - Support for JFS file system.<br/>
        <br/>
        GeeXboX 1.1 (for x86 computers only) is available
        <a href="downloads.html">here</a> and right now!
      </content>
    </subsection>

  </section>
</article>
