<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE article [
<!ENTITY % geexboxent  SYSTEM "geexbox.dtd">
%geexboxent;
<!ENTITY % HTMLlat1 PUBLIC
	 "-//W3C//ENTITIES Latin 1 for XHTML//EN"
	 "http://www.w3.org/TR/xhtml1/DTD/xhtml-lat1.ent">
%HTMLlat1;
]>

<article>

  <define name="scr-enna">
    <center>
      <a href="../img/mainmenu-music.jpg">
        <img src="../img/mainmenu-music-thumb.jpg" border="0" alt="Enna Music Menu"/>
      </a>
      <a href="../img/activity-photo-wall.jpg">
        <img src="../img/activity-photo-wall-thumb.jpg" border="0" alt="Enna Photo Wall"/>
      </a>
      <a href="../img/activity-video-infos.jpg">
        <img src="../img/activity-video-infos-thumb.jpg" border="0" alt="Enna Video Info"/>
      </a>
    </center>
  </define>

  <define name="fosdem">
    <a href="http://www.fosdem.org/">FOSDEM (Free and Open Source Software Developers' European Meeting)</a>
  </define>
  <define name="fosdem2010_slides">
    <a href="http://geexbox.org/~ben/FOSDEM%202010%20-%20BZ%20%20An%20Introduction%20to%20Enna%20MediaCenter.pdf">slides</a>
  </define>
  <define name="fosdem2010_video">
    <a href="http://geexbox.org/~ben/16-sat-geexbox.xvid.avi">video</a>
  </define>

  <define name="release_2.0_alpha2-i386">
    <a href="http://www1.geexbox.org/releases/2.0-alpha2/geexbox-2.0-alpha2-en.i386.eglibc.iso">i386</a>
  </define>
  <define name="release_2.0_alpha2-x86_64">
    <a href="http://www1.geexbox.org/releases/2.0-alpha2/geexbox-2.0-alpha2-en.x86_64.eglibc.iso">x86_64</a>
  </define>

  <define name="release_2.0_alpha2-src-lite">
    <a href="http://www1.geexbox.org/releases/2.0-alpha2/geexbox-2.0-alpha2-lite.tar.bz2">light</a>
  </define>
  <define name="release_2.0_alpha2-src-full">
    <a href="http://www1.geexbox.org/releases/2.0-alpha2/geexbox-2.0-alpha2-full.tar">full</a>
  </define>

  <define name="release_2.0_win32_installer-23">
    <a href="http://www1.geexbox.org/releases/win32-installer/0.23/geexbox-win32-installer-0.23.exe">Windows</a>
  </define>

  <define name="release_2.0_alpha1-i386">
    <a href="http://www1.geexbox.org/releases/2.0-alpha1/geexbox-2.0-alpha1-en.i386.eglibc.iso">i386</a>
  </define>
  <define name="release_2.0_alpha1-x86_64">
    <a href="http://www1.geexbox.org/releases/2.0-alpha1/geexbox-2.0-alpha1-en.x86_64.eglibc.iso">x86_64</a>
  </define>

  <define name="release_2.0_alpha1-src-lite">
    <a href="http://www1.geexbox.org/releases/2.0-alpha1/geexbox-2.0-alpha1-lite.tar.bz2">light</a>
  </define>
  <define name="release_2.0_alpha1-src-full">
    <a href="http://www1.geexbox.org/releases/2.0-alpha1/geexbox-2.0-alpha1-full.tar">full</a>
  </define>

  <define name="enna">
    <a href="http://enna.geexbox.org/">Enna</a>
  </define>

  <section label="news">
    <content lang="en" title="Latest News ..."/>
    <content lang="fr" title="Dernières Nouvelles ..."/>
    <content lang="de" title="Aktuelle Nachrichten ..."/>

    <subsection label="what_is_geexbox">
      <content lang="en" title="What is GeeXboX ?">
        GeeXboX is a free embedded Linux distribution which aims at
        turning your computer into a so called HTPC (Home Theater PC)
        or Media Center. Being a standalone LiveCD-based distribution,
        it's a ready to boot operating system than works on any
        Pentium-class x86 computer or PowerPC Macintosh, implying no software
        requirement. You can even use it on a diskless computer, the
        whole system being loaded in RAM.
        <br/><br/>
        Despite his tiny ISO image size, the distribution comes with a
        complete and automatic hardware detection, not requiring any
        driver to be added. It supports playback of nearly any kind of
        audio/video and image files and all known codecs and
        containers are shipped in, allowing playing them through
        various physical supports, either being CD, DVD, HDD, LAN or
        Internet.
        <br/><br/>
        GeeXboX also comes with a complete toolchain that allows
        developers adding easily extra packages and features but that
        might also be used to give birth to many dedicated embedded
        Linux systems.
      </content>
      <content lang="fr" title="Qu'est ce que la GeeXboX ?">
        La GeeXboX est une distribution Linux libre et à caractère
        embarqué qui se propose de transformer votre ordinateur en ce
        que l'on nomme désormais un HTPC (Home Theater PC) ou encore
        Media Center. Etant distribuée sous la forme d'un CD
        auto-amorçable, il s'agit d'un système d'exploitation prêt à
        l'emploi, capable de fonctionner sur tout type de PC de classe
        Pentium et supérieure ou encore de Macintosh à base de
        PowerPC, le tout ne nécessitant aucun autre logiciel. Il vous
        sera également possible de l'utiliser sur un ordinateur
        dépourvu de disque dur, le système étant intégralement chargé
        en mémoire.
        <br/><br/>
        En dépit de la très petite taille de son image ISO, la
        distribution propose une reconnaissance complète et
        automatisée de votre configuration matérielle, ne nécessitant
        donc l'ajout d'aucun pilote de périphérique particulier. Le
        système supporte la lecture de la quasi totalité des formats
        audio/vidéo ou d'images existants et, l'ensemble des codecs et
        containeurs multimédias connus y sont intégrés. Il est
        également possible de lire vos contenus depuis des sources
        très variées comme par exemple un CD, un DVD, votre (vos)
        disque(s) dur(s) (locaux ou distants), votre réseau local ou
        encore directement depuis Internet.
        <br/><br/>
        La GeeXboX est également accompagnée d'une chaîne de
        cross-compilation complète, permettant aux développeurs de
        très facilement étendre ses fonctionnalités, d'y ajouter des
        paquetages, ou encore de le réutiliser pour donner naissance à
        de nouveaux systèmes Linux embarqués dédiés.
      </content>
    </subsection>

    <subsection label="geexbox_2.0_alpha2" date="2010-03-13">
      <content lang="en" title="GeeXboX 2.0-alpha2 release">
        It's already been one month since 2.0-alpha1 release so here's alpha2.
        This release fixes a lot of bugs that have been encountered by our
        users on this first 2.x series preview.<br/>
        <ul>
          <li>Normalize LIRC configuration by providing generic binding for
            each and every remote control.</li>
          <li>Initial port to ARM architecture: stay tuned, it's gonna be
            awesome news soon :-)</li>
          <li>Restoration of UPnP/DLNA feature with a brand new stack.</li>
          <li>Upgrade of nVidia drivers: proprietary, legacy one and
            addition of Nouveau.</li>
          <li>Add Kernel Mode Settings (KMS) for ATI/Intel/nVidia drivers.</li>
          <li>Upgrade to Linux 2.6.33 kernel.</li>
          <li>Fix LiveCD and Win32 installers, you can now install GeeXboX
            to disk again.</li>
          <li>Fix OGG files playback issue.</li>
          <li>Upgrade Enna to future upcoming 0.5.0 release, including hundreds
            of bug fixes and new features such as Weather enhancements, GeoIP
            localization, UPnP support, SHOUTcast and Podcast streaming.</li>
        </ul>
        <br/>
        Generator is still not yet ready for prime-time but we're
        working on it. That said, feel free to download this new 2.0-alpha2
        release. It had been made available for
        <use name="release_2.0_alpha2-i386"/>
        and <use name="release_2.0_alpha2-x86_64"/> computers.
        The <use name="release_2.0_alpha2-src-lite"/> and
        <use name="release_2.0_alpha2-src-full"/> sources of this release
        obviously are available too.<br/>
        <br/>
        You can also install it without further disk partitionning through the
        <use name="release_2.0_win32_installer-23"/> installer.
        <br/>
      </content>
    </subsection>

    <subsection label="geexbox_2.0_alpha1" date="2010-02-14">
      <content lang="en" title="GeeXboX 2.0-alpha1 release">
        This has been announced for years but we're finally stepping forward to
        the so long awaited for 2.0 release of GeeXboX. Today, we're proud to
        let you have a first try at this new version, based on the
        <use name="enna"/> Media Center application that we have
        developed.<br/>
        <br/>
        Enna is a standalone application that one can use on any Linux
        distribution (soon to be available for MacOSX and Windows users, who
        knows ...) that replaces the old and dying MPlayer OSD interface we've
        been using for so long. The GeeXboX distribution you all know about
        will then become the Enna Live-CD project, but with all optimizations,
        configuration and tweakings that one may be able to do on his regular
        computer.<br/>
        <br/>
        With Enna, GeeXboX now looks promising again, with this new shiny look
        and feel interface. Also being much more nicer, Enna allows us to add
        so many new features that you all were waiting for (check out the
        <use name="enna"/> website for that) so future looks bright again.<br/>
        <br/>
        Also, Enna has been designed to be simple and intuitive to be used.
        It can be controlled either through keyboard, mouse or remote control.
        Mouse support is quite new in GeeXboX but its usage is kinda trivial.
        As for keyboard, we have tried to make usable with as few keys as
        possible. As a result, one can control Enna the following way:<br/>
        <br/>
        <ul>
          <li>Arrows: used to navigate between the different menu lists.</li>
          <li>Enter: used to validate your selection.</li>
          <li>Backspace: used to cancel or browse back to previous menu.</li>
          <li>Escape: if you ever wanna stop Enna (and shutdown GeeXboX
            as well).</li>
        </ul>
        <br/>
        <use name="scr-enna"/>
        <br/>
        As you might have understood, Enna and GeeXboX v2.x design is the
        result of years of development and deep architectural changes.
        Things now are getting stabilized but we're still lacking of manpower
        to enhance it the way we'd like it to be. So if you're a Linux
        developer, feel free to join our team. If you're interested in GeeXboX
        v2.x architecture, you'd be glad to know that it was presented to
        <use name="fosdem"/> a week ago and both
        <use name="fosdem2010_slides"/> and <use name="fosdem2010_video"/>
        are available.<br/>
        <br/>
        We all hope you'll enjoy this first alpha release of GeeXboX 2.x
        series. Though, keep in mind that, as the name suggests, it's an alpha
        version only. This means that unfortunately, it still suffers a lot of
        bugs and many regressions towards 1.x series. The availability of final
        stable release over requires you to test it the most you can,
        reporting any trouble one can find.<br/>
        <br/>
        As a consequence, some stuff are already know to be broken or
        missing:<br/>
        <ul>
          <li>Some features are disabled, including TV and netstreams
            support.</li>
          <li>Generator needs a huge rewrite and will be part of alpha2
            release only, sorry folks.</li>
          <li>Audio OGG files are seen as video files (!!) and playing them
            back results in a black screen with uncontrollable Enna
            (you've warned).</li>
          <li>The framebuffer-based console mode has been disabled until being
            fixed. HDTV mode only (i.e. using X.Org server) is supported in
            this version.</li>
        </ul>
        <br/>
        On the bright side, new features have been added or enabled by
        default:<br/>
        <ul>
          <li>The proprietary nVidia video driver has been integrated.
            Every nVidia GPU should now be supported. With those cards, Enna
            should also be using its OpenGL rendering engine, providing a
            smooth rendering.</li>
          <li>The VDPAU hardware decoding engine has been integrated. If you're
            the lucky owner of an nVidia card higher than GF8800 series,
            than you should be able to decode MPEG-2, MPEG-4 (i.e. DivX), H.264
            and VC-1 streams using your video card, offloading your CPU.
            This of course includes ION-based Set-Top-Boxes that are now able
            to decode 1080p videos.</li>
          <li>For non-nVidia users, the multi-threaded decoding feature now has
            been enabled by default. MPlayer will then uses all of your CPU's
            cores to do software video decoding.</li>
        </ul>
        <br/>
        In order to allow us to enhance GeeXboX to our users' configuration,
        we've also setup a statistics utility that provides us with some
        information regarding your hardware configuration. It has been enabled
        by default but we know that it can be intrusive for some users. So if
        you're not willing to provide these info (CPU model, amount of memory
        RAM, video board type, and such ...), you can disable it by adding
        <b>nostats</b> to the boot command-line.<br/>
        <br/>
        That said, feel free to download our new 2.0-alpha1 release.
        It had been made available for <use name="release_2.0_alpha1-i386"/>
        and <use name="release_2.0_alpha1-x86_64"/> computers.
        The <use name="release_2.0_alpha1-src-lite"/> and
        <use name="release_2.0_alpha1-src-full"/> sources of this release
        obviously are available too.
      </content>
    </subsection>

    <subsection label="enna_0.4.0" date="2010-01-03">
      <content lang="en" title="Initial release of Enna: v0.4.0">
        It was kinda hard and efforts were countless, but GeeXboX team is proud
        to announce the very stable release of <use name="enna"/> Media Center.
        After months of development, this brand new user interface finally has
        landed. Enna is available as a standalone application for all modern
        GNU/Linux based distributions (and already packaged for Ubuntu 9.10)
        and will, obviously, be part of GeeXboX v2.0 release. Speaking of
        which, the hardest part now being behind us, the first Alpha1 release
        of GeeXboX v2 is due to this month.<br/>
        <br/>
        In the mean time, feel free to test Enna on your regular PC and we
        really hope you'll enjoy using it. More information are of course
        available on <use name="enna"/> website.
      </content>
      <content lang="fr" title="Disponibilité d'Enna v0.4.0">
        Cela aura pris du temps et un nombre incalculable d'efforts, mais
        l'équipe GeeXboX est fière d'annoncer la disponibilité de la toute
        première version stable d'<use name="enna"/> Media Center. Après des
        mois de développement, cette toute nouvelle interface graphique a
        finalement vue le jour. Enna est disponible sous la forme d'une
        application autonome pour toute distribution GNU/Linux moderne (et
        dores et déjà empaquetée pour Ubuntu 9.10) et fera, bien évidemment,
        partie de la release 2.0 de la GeeXboX. En parlant de cela, le plus
        gros du travail étant désormais derrière nous, la première version
        Alpha1 de notre distribution devrait voir le jour dans le courant du
        mois.<br/>
        <br/>
        En attendant, laissez vous aller à tester Enna sur votre PC quotidien
        and nous espérons vraiment que vous apprécierez son utilisation.
        De plus amples informations sont bien évidemment disponible sur la
        page dédiée du projet <use name="enna"/>.
      </content>
    </subsection>

  </section>
</article>
