<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE article [
<!ENTITY % geexboxent  SYSTEM "geexbox.dtd">
%geexboxent;
<!ENTITY % HTMLlat1 PUBLIC
	 "-//W3C//ENTITIES Latin 1 for XHTML//EN"
	 "http://www.w3.org/TR/xhtml1/DTD/xhtml-lat1.ent">
%HTMLlat1;
]>

<article>

  <define name="sherkhan_release_20061231">
    <a href="http://www.geexbox.org/~ben/v2/geexbox-sherkhan-20061231-en.i386.iso"><b>GeeXboX 2.x 2006-12-31</b></a>
  </define>

  <define name="open_usability">
    <a href="http://www.openusability.org/"><b>OpenUsability</b></a>
  </define>

  <define name="open_usability_season_07">
    <a href="http://www.openusability.org/season/0607/season0607_openings.html#geexbox"><b>Season of Usability 2007</b></a>
  </define>

  <define name="open_usability_survey_en">
    <a href="http://85.10.193.9/UCCASS/survey.php?sid=39"><b>survey</b></a>
  </define>

  <define name="open_usability_survey_fr">
    <a href="http://85.10.193.9/UCCASS/survey.php?sid=39"><b>questionnaire</b></a>
  </define>

  <define name="open_usability_survey_results">
    <a href="http://www.geexbox.org/~ben/User%20Survey%20Results%20-%20Francesco%20De%20Rose.pdf"><b>OpenUsability</b></a>
  </define>

  <define name="gsoc_2007">
    <a href="http://code.google.com/soc/freevo/about.html"><b>Google Summer Of Code 2007</b></a>
  </define>

  <define name="scr-freevo">
    <center>
      <a href="../img/freevo-scr-menu.png">
        <img src="../img/freevo-scr-menu-thumb.png" alt="GeeXboX 2.x
        Main Menu"/>
      </a>
      <a href="../img/freevo-scr-video.png">
        <img src="../img/freevo-scr-video-thumb.png" alt="GeeXboX 2.x
        Video Menu"/>
      </a>
      <a href="../img/freevo-scr-audio.png">
        <img src="../img/freevo-scr-audio-thumb.png" alt="GeeXboX 2.x
        Audio Menu"/>
      </a>
      <a href="../img/freevo-scr-image.png">
        <img src="../img/freevo-scr-image-thumb.png" alt="GeeXboX 2.x
        Image Menu"/>
      </a>
    </center>
  </define>

  <define name="geexbox_1.1_rc1_x86_iso">
    <a href="http://www.geexbox.org/releases/1.1-rc1/geexbox-1.1rc1-en.i386.iso"><b>GeeXboX 1.1-rc1 ISO for i386</b></a>
  </define>

  <define name="geexbox_1.1_rc1_x86_generator">
    <a href="http://www.geexbox.org/releases/1.1-rc1/geexbox-generator-1.1rc1.i386.tar.gz"><b>GeeXboX 1.1-rc1 ISO Generator for i386</b></a>
  </define>

  <define name="geexbox_1.1_rc1_ppc_iso">
    <a href="http://www.geexbox.org/releases/1.1-rc1/geexbox-1.1rc1-en.ppc.iso"><b>GeeXboX 1.1-rc1 ISO for PowerPC</b></a>
  </define>

  <define name="geexbox_1.1_rc1_ppc_generator">
    <a href="http://www.geexbox.org/releases/1.1-rc1/geexbox-generator-1.1rc1.ppc.tar.gz"><b>GeeXboX 1.1-rc1 ISO Generator for PowerPC</b></a>
  </define>

  <define name="geexbox_1.1_rc1_src">
    <a href="http://www.geexbox.org/releases/1.1-rc1/geexbox-1.1rc1-lite.tar.bz2"><b>GeeXboX 1.1-rc1 Light Sources</b></a>
  </define>

  <define name="geexbox_1.1_rc1_forum_en">
    <a href="http://www.geexbox.org/forum/viewtopic.php?t=8320"><b>Forum</b></a>
  </define>

  <define name="geexbox_1.1_rc1_forum_fr">
    <a href="http://www.geexbox.org/forum/viewtopic.php?t=8321"><b>Forum</b></a>
  </define>

  <define name="geexbox_1.1_rc2_x86_iso">
    <a href="http://www.geexbox.org/releases/1.1-rc2/geexbox-1.1-rc2-en.i386.iso"><b>GeeXboX 1.1-rc2 ISO for i386</b></a>
  </define>

  <define name="geexbox_1.1_rc2_x86_generator">
    <a href="http://www.geexbox.org/releases/1.1-rc2/geexbox-generator-1.1-rc2.i386.tar.gz"><b>GeeXboX 1.1-rc2 ISO Generator for i386</b></a>
  </define>

  <define name="geexbox_1.1_rc2_ppc_iso">
    <a href="http://www.geexbox.org/releases/1.1-rc2/geexbox-1.1-rc2-en.ppc.iso"><b>GeeXboX 1.1-rc2 ISO for PowerPC</b></a>
  </define>

  <define name="geexbox_1.1_rc2_ppc_generator">
    <a href="http://www.geexbox.org/releases/1.1-rc2/geexbox-generator-1.1-rc2.ppc.tar.gz"><b>GeeXboX 1.1-rc2 ISO Generator for PowerPC</b></a>
  </define>

  <define name="geexbox_1.1_rc2_src">
    <a href="http://www.geexbox.org/releases/1.1-rc2/geexbox-1.1-rc2-lite.tar.bz2"><b>GeeXboX 1.1-rc2 Light Sources</b></a>
  </define>

  <define name="geexbox_1.1_rc2_forum_en">
    <a href="http://www.geexbox.org/forum/viewtopic.php?p=45941"><b>Forum</b></a>
  </define>

  <define name="geexbox_1.1_rc2_forum_fr">
    <a href="http://www.geexbox.org/forum/viewtopic.php?p=45942"><b>Forum</b></a>
  </define>

  <define name="geexbox_xorg_beta1_en">
    <a href="http://www.geexbox.org/forum/viewtopic.php?t=8700"><b>Forum</b></a>
  </define>

  <define name="geexbox_xorg_beta1_fr">
    <a href="http://www.geexbox.org/forum/viewtopic.php?t=8701"><b>Forum</b></a>
  </define>

  <section label="news">
    <content lang="en" title="Latest News ..."/>
    <content lang="fr" title="Dernières Nouvelles ..."/>
    <content lang="de" title="Aktuelle Nachrichten ..."/>

    <subsection label="what_is_geexbox">
      <content lang="en" title="What is GeeXboX ?">
        GeeXboX is a free embedded Linux distribution which aims at
        turning your computer into a so called HTPC (Home Theater PC)
        or Media Center. Being a standalone LiveCD-based distribution,
        it's a ready to boot operating system than works on any
        Pentium-class x86 computer or PowerPC Macintosh, implying no software
        requirement. You can even use it on a diskless computer, the
        whole system being loaded in RAM.
        <br/><br/>
        Despite his tiny ISO image size, the distribution comes with a
        complete and automatic hardware detection, not requiring any
        driver to be added. It supports playback of nearly any kind of
        audio/video and image files and all known codecs and
        containers are shipped in, allowing playing them through
        various physical supports, either being CD, DVD, HDD, LAN or
        Internet.
        <br/><br/>
        GeeXboX also comes with a complete toolchain that allows
        developers adding easily extra packages and features but that
        might also be used to give birth to many dedicated embedded
        Linux systems.
      </content>
      <content lang="fr" title="Qu'est ce que la GeeXboX ?">
        La GeeXboX est une distribution Linux libre et à caractère
        embarqué qui se propose de transformer votre ordinateur en ce
        que l'on nomme désormais un HTPC (Home Theater PC) ou encore
        Media Center. Etant distribuée sous la forme d'un CD
        auto-amorçable, il s'agit d'un système d'exploitation prêt à
        l'emploi, capable de fonctionner sur tout type de PC de classe
        Pentium et supérieure ou encore de Macintosh à base de
        PowerPC, le tout ne nécessitant aucun autre logiciel. Il vous
        sera également possible de l'utiliser sur un ordinateur
        dépourvu de disque dur, le système étant intégralement chargé
        en mémoire.
        <br/><br/>
        En dépit de la très petite taille de son image ISO, la
        distribution propose une reconnaissance complète et
        automatisée de votre configuration matérielle, ne nécessitant
        donc l'ajout d'aucun pilote de périphérique particulier. Le
        système supporte la lecture de la quasi totalité des formats
        audio/vidéo ou d'images existants et, l'ensemble des codecs et
        containeurs multimédias connus y sont intégrés. Il est
        également possible de lire vos contenus depuis des sources
        très variées comme par exemple un CD, un DVD, votre (vos)
        disque(s) dur(s) (locaux ou distants), votre réseau local ou
        encore directement depuis Internet.
        <br/><br/>
        La GeeXboX est également accompagnée d'une chaîne de
        cross-compilation complète, permettant aux développeurs de
        très facilement étendre ses fonctionnalités, d'y ajouter des
        paquetages, ou encore de le réutiliser pour donner naissance à
        de nouveaux systèmes Linux embarqués dédiés.
      </content>
    </subsection>

    <subsection label="geexbox_xorg_beta1" date="2007-05-08">
      <content lang="en" title="First beta of HDTV Ready GeeXboX">
        According to recent user survey, you were more and more asking for a
        proper HDTV support. So finally here it is. Let's introduce the first
        beta of the HDTV Ready GeeXboX (based on 1.x version). Please have a
        try at it but also remember it's only a beta (no release date). More
        informations can be found on <use name="geexbox_xorg_beta1_en"/>.
      </content>
      <content lang="fr" title="Première version beta de la GeeXboX compatible HDTV">
        D'après les résultats du récent sondage utilisateur, vous êtes de plus
        en plus nombreux à attendre de la GeeXboX un support de la haute
        définition. Et le voici donc ! Vous pouvez donc dès à présent tester
        cette première version beta de la GeeXboX "HD" (basé sur la version
        1.x). N'oubliez pas cependant que cela reste une béta, avec tout ce
        que cela implique. Plus d'informations sont disponibles sur le
        <use name="geexbox_xorg_beta1_fr"/>.
      </content>
    </subsection>

    <subsection label="gsoc_07_acceptation" date="2007-04-11">
      <content lang="en" title="GeeXboX/Freevo has been accepted to Google Summer Of Code 2007">
        Great news, the GeeXboX/Freevo project has been accepted for the
        <use name="gsoc_2007"/>. This means that we'll have 4 students working
        on several aspects of both projects to extend their capabilities.
        Let's introduce the projects:<br/><br/>
        * <b>LiveCD boot and HDD installation process</b> by Adir
        Abraham.<br/>
        * <b>Controlling Freevo through a simple web interface</b> by
        Ky Phan.<br/>
        * <b>DVB CAM support</b> by Alessandro Decina.<br/>
        * <b>Gstreamer Integration</b> by Killian Faughnan<br/>
        <br/>
        Welcome to these students and good luck to everyone for their
        projects.
      </content>
      <content lang="fr" title="GeeXboX/Freevo a été accepté au Google Summer Of Code 2007">
        Bonne nouvelle ! Le projet GeeXboX/Freevo a été accepté au
        <use name="gsoc_2007"/>. Cela signifie que nous disposons de 4
        étudiants qui vont chacun travailler sur différents aspects du projet
        afin de toujours l'améliorer. Voici donc l'ensemble des projets
        retenus:<br/><br/>
        * <b>Ré-écriture de la procédure de démarrage et de l'installation sur
        disque</b> par Adir Abraham.<br/>
        * <b>Contrôle de Freevo via une interface Web</b> par Ky Phan.<br/>
        * <b>Support des modules CAM pour le DVB</b> par Alessandro
        Decina.<br/>
        * <b>Intégration de Gstreamer</b> par Killian Faughnan<br/>
        <br/>
        Bienvenue à ces étudiants et bonne chance à chacun pour leur projet.
      </content>
    </subsection>

    <subsection label="open_usability_survey_release" date="2007-03-27">
      <content lang="en" title="GeeXboX user survey: here are the results (posted by Francesco)">
        At last here it is... we have been analysing the data we gathered
        during the user survey, and we found out many interesting thing about
        you! First of all, you are many more than we imagined, and you are
        very responsive and involved: thank you for your interest and
        participation! And then where and how you user GeeXboX, what you like
        the most, what your strongest needs are... Are you curious to have a
        look at the survey report? Then download it! You can find it at
        <use name="open_usability_survey_results"/>
      </content>
      <content lang="fr" title="Sondage utilisateur GeeXboX: et voici les résultats (par Francesco)">
        Avec beaucoup de retard, les voici enfin ... Nous avons analysés les
        données que nous avons pu récolter au cours de ce sondage utilisateur
        et cela nous a permis de découvrir beaucoup de choses sur vous ! Tout
        d'abord, vous êtes bien plus nombreux à avoir répondu et à utiliser la
        GeeXboX que nous aurions pu l'imaginer, mais vous êtes également très
        impliqués: un grand merci pour votre intérêt et votre participation au
        projet. Pour les plus curieux d'entre vous, les résultats de cette
        étude sont disponibles (en anglais néanmoins) via le projet
        <use name="open_usability_survey_results"/>.
      </content>
    </subsection>

    <subsection label="open_usability_survey_end" date="2007-03-04">
      <content lang="en" title="GeeXboX user survey: thanks for your (posted by Francesco)">
        The GeeXboX user survey is now closed. We have received many more
        responses than we would have ever hoped for, and this means that we
        have a great user base. We really wish to thank all of you for your
        help; now we have to get working and make good use of your responses:
        hopefully you'll be able to see the effects very soon!
      </content>
      <content lang="fr" title="Sondage utilisateur GeeXboX: un grand merci pour vos réponses (par Francesco)">
        Le sondage d'utilisation GeeXboX est désormais terminé. Nous avons
        reçu bien plus de réponses que nous n'en aurions espéré, et cela
        prouve bien à quel point notre base d'utilisateurs est conséquente.
        Nous souhaitons tous vous remercier pour l'aide que vous nous avez
        apporté. Il est maintenant temps pour nous de se remettre au travail
        et de faire bon usage de vous réponses. Attendez vous donc à avoir les
        résultats de cette enquête au plus vite !
      </content>
    </subsection>

    <subsection label="geexbox_1.1_rc2" date="2007-03-01">
      <content lang="en" title="GeeXboX 1.1-rc2 released: (re)call for test.">
        Thanks to your 1.1-rc1 testings, we've been able to fix out a lot of
        bugs from GeeXboX. It is now up to you to test this new release again.
        Once again, please test this version and report problems
        to the <use name="geexbox_1.1_rc2_forum_en"/>. As usual, the
        more you'll be to test it, the faster we'll release 1.1.<br/>
        <br/>
        Below are links to 1.1-rc2:<br/>
        - <use name="geexbox_1.1_rc2_x86_iso"/><br/>
        - <use name="geexbox_1.1_rc2_x86_generator"/><br/>
        - <use name="geexbox_1.1_rc2_ppc_iso"/><br/>
        - <use name="geexbox_1.1_rc2_ppc_generator"/><br/>
        - <use name="geexbox_1.1_rc2_src"/><br/>
      </content>
      <content lang="fr" title="GeeXboX version 1.1-rc2: (r)appel à test.">
        Grâce à vos nombreux tests de la version 1.1-rc1, nous avons pu
        corriger un certain nombre de fonctionnalités qui n'avaient pas le
        comportement attendu. L'heure est aujourd'hui à la version 1.1-rc2,
        dont nous souhaitons votre avis. Encore une fois, veuillez tester
        cette version et nous signaler les problèmes rencontrés sur le
        <use name="geexbox_1.1_rc2_forum_fr"/>. Comme d'habitude, plus vous
        la testerez, et plus vite la 1.1 sera disponible. 
        <br/>
        Voici donc les liens vers la version 1.1-rc2:<br/>
        - <use name="geexbox_1.1_rc2_x86_iso"/><br/>
        - <use name="geexbox_1.1_rc2_x86_generator"/><br/>
        - <use name="geexbox_1.1_rc2_ppc_iso"/><br/>
        - <use name="geexbox_1.1_rc2_ppc_generator"/><br/>
        - <use name="geexbox_1.1_rc2_src"/><br/>
      </content>
    </subsection>

    <subsection label="open_usability_survey" date="2007-02-22">
      <content lang="en" title="GeeXboX user survey: make your voice heard (posted by Francesco)">
        Within the OpenUsability project, we are deploying a user survey in order to get to know our users better so that we can improve the user interface. We currently are in the process to restructure GeeXboX in order to render it more usable: that is, we want you to be able to use GeeXboX more easily, quickly and with more satisfaction and enjoyment. So, please spend five minutes of your time and answer the questions that you can find on this <use name="open_usability_survey_en"/>.<br/>
        <br/>
        Thank you in advance for your involvement. 
      </content>
      <content lang="fr" title="Sondage utilisateur GeeXboX: faites vous entendre (par Francesco)">
        Par le biais du projet OpenUsability, nous sommes en train de déployer une enquête, dans le but de connaitre davantage nos utilisateurs, de mieux les comprendre, et ainsi d'améliorer notre interface. Nous sommes actuellement en plein processus de restructuration de la GeeXboX avec le développement de la version 2.x et ce, dans le but de la rendre toujorus plus pratique d'emploi. De ce fait, nous souhaitons améliorer notre distribution pour la rendre plus facile et rapide d'utilisation, afin de vous donner plus de satisfaction. Nous vous remerçions donc de bien vouloir nous accorder 5 minutes de votre temps pour répondre à ce petit <use name="open_usability_survey_fr"/>.<br/>
        <br/>
        En vous remerçiant de votre participation. 
      </content>
    </subsection>

    <subsection label="geexbox_1.1_rc1" date="2007-02-03">
      <content lang="en" title="GeeXboX 1.1-rc1 released: call for test.">
        While the team is working on 2.x series achievement, the 1.x
        series has continued to evolve and here's the first release
        candidate of the upcoming 1.1 version. In order for us to
        discover the remaining nasty bugs and help us release 1.1 as
        soon as possible, please test this version and report problems
        to the <use name="geexbox_1.1_rc1_forum_en"/>. As usual, the
        more you'll be to test it, the faster we'll release 1.1.<br/>
        <br/>
        Below are links to 1.1-rc1:<br/>
        - <use name="geexbox_1.1_rc1_x86_iso"/><br/>
        - <use name="geexbox_1.1_rc1_x86_generator"/><br/>
        - <use name="geexbox_1.1_rc1_ppc_iso"/><br/>
        - <use name="geexbox_1.1_rc1_ppc_generator"/><br/>
        - <use name="geexbox_1.1_rc1_src"/><br/>
      </content>
      <content lang="fr" title="GeeXboX version 1.1-rc1: appel à test.">
        Alors que l'équipe continue de travailler sur les fondements
        de la version 2.x, la branche 1.x a continué d'évoluer et
        voici arriver la première version d'évaluation de la future 1.1.
        Dans le but de nous aider à découvrir et corriger les derniers
        bugs et nous aider à mettre au point la version 1.1 finale au
        plus vite, vous êtes tous invités à tester cette version et à
        signaler les problèmes rencontrés sur le <use
        name="geexbox_1.1_rc1_forum_fr"/>. Comme d'habitude, plus vous
        la testerez, et plus vite la 1.1 sera disponible. 
        <br/>
        Voici donc les liens vers la version 1.1-rc1:<br/>
        - <use name="geexbox_1.1_rc1_x86_iso"/><br/>
        - <use name="geexbox_1.1_rc1_x86_generator"/><br/>
        - <use name="geexbox_1.1_rc1_ppc_iso"/><br/>
        - <use name="geexbox_1.1_rc1_ppc_generator"/><br/>
        - <use name="geexbox_1.1_rc1_src"/><br/>
      </content>
    </subsection>

    <subsection label="open_usability_07" date="2007-01-05">
      <content lang="en" title="Open Usability Season '07 acceptance:
        sponsored student came in.">
        The GeeXboX project has been accepted to the <use
        name="open_usability"/>, <use name="open_usability_season_07"/>
        program. As a result, we are proud to welcome a student,
        <b>Francesco De Rose</b>, that will work with our team on usability
        concerns, especially dealing on GeeXboX 2.x interface. He will
        be mentored by <b>Celeste Lyn Paul</b>, an interaction architect,
        active contributor to the KDE Usability Project and
        OpenUsability. Francesco might start collecting user feedback
        in order to help us extend GeeXboX and make always the most
        easy and intuitive to use we can.
      </content>
      <content lang="fr" title="Acceptation au projet Open Usability,
        Saison 2007 : bienvenue à notre nouvel étudiant.">
        Le projet GeeXboX a été sélectionné par <use
        name="open_usability"/>, pour son programme <use
        name="open_usability_season_07"/>. Il en découle l'arrivée
        d'un nouvel étudiant, <b>Francesco De Rose</b>, que nous
        sommes heureux d'acceuillir au sein de l'équipe, et qui va
        travailler sur les aspects d'utilisation et d'accessibilité,
        le tout orienté bien entendu, sur l'interface de la version
        2.x à venir. Il sera aidé et sous la responsabilité de
        <b>Celeste Lyn Paul</b>, architecte responsable de
        l'interaction entre projets et également contributeuse active
        au projet d'accessibilité KDE et bien entendu à OpenUsability.
        Francesco devrait commencer par recueillir les impressions de
        nombreux utilisateurs, ce qui nous aidera à mieux cerner
        besoins et problèmes et à améliorer la GeeXboX, de sorte à la
        rendre toujours plus intuitive et simple d'emploi.
      </content>
    </subsection>

    <subsection label="sherkhan_preview1" date="2006-12-31">
      <content lang="en" title="GeeXboX 2.x technological preview:
        what a surprise !">
        Xmas passed away and no new GeeXboX release came out this
        year. It's a bit sad but we were focusing on next generation
        architecture which delayed a bit the 1.x serie development.
        You may however expect some 1.1 release any time soon, with
        it's usual set of improvements. Time has come now to let you
        discover our very first technological preview of GeeXboX 2.x
        series.<br/>
        <br/>
        Some of you may have heard about MPUI years ago, or
        OMC/libplayer a bit earlier this year but both approaches went
        down. The decision has been taken to make use of Freevo 2.0
        (still work in progress, but so is GeeXboX 2.x) and Kaa, its
        multimedia framework as our new UI reference. As a consequence,
        many new packages had to be added (such as Python) to our
        distribution. In a near future, GeeXboX and Freevo projects
        will be more tighten than ever, and we should be the official
        Freevo LiveCD, still keeping in mind our embedded and
        easy-to-setup approach. Unfortunately, ISO grew up radically
        (it is now 20 MB) and so does RAM usage (at least 128MB is now
        mandatory). But, as a development version, don't take it too
        seriously, it'll still change 'till the final release. If you
        want to have a try at this technological preview, just grab the
        <use name="sherkhan_release_20061231"/> ISO and burn it to a
        CD or try it through VMware or so. Don't look for a generator
        or try to install it on disk, it is not yet meant for. Don't
        expect it either to be fully functional, it's still full of
        bugs and isn't meant to replace the official 1.x serie anytime
        soon. Right now, it can be controlled through keyboard only
        (arrow keys and Enter/Escape) but should already be able to
        let you watch some videos, play audio files or view various
        pictures. Well, that's said, here are some screenshots, just
        for you to know what to expect from 2007 ;-)<br/>
        <br/>
        <use name="scr-freevo"/>
        <br/>
        Happy new year from all the GeeXboX team members ...
      </content>
      <content lang="fr" title="GeeXboX 2.x, première démo technologique: ça
        pour une surprise ...">
        Noël est passé et n'aura, pour une fois, apporté aucune
        nouvelle version de la GeeXboX. C'est un peu triste mais
        c'est essentiellement dû au fait que nous consacrons
        aujourd'hui nos efforts sur la nouvelle architecture GeeXboX,
        ce qui retarde quelques peu, la branche 1.x. Vous pouvez
        néanmoins vous attendre à la sortie prochaine de la version
        1.1 qui, comme d'habitude, apportera son lot de corrections et
        améliorations. Mais pour l'heure, il est temps de vous faire
        découvrir notre toute première démonstration technologique de
        ce que sera la future série 2.x de la GeeXboX.<br/>
        <br/>
        Les plus fidèles ont pu, par le passé, entendre parler de MPUI
        ou encore du couple OMC/libplayer, qui furent 2 approches pour
        la nouvelle interface qui ont toutes 2 échouées pour des
        raisons diverses et variées. La décision a récemment été prise
        de choisir Freevo 2.0 (toujours à l'état de développement,
        mais c'est également le cas de la GeeXboX 2.x) ainsi que Kaa,
        sa base multimédia, comme les fondations de notre future interface.
        Il en résulte que de nombreux paquetages ont ainsi dû être
        ajoutés (tels que Python) à la distribution. Dans un futur
        proche, les projets GeeXboX et Freevo seront très liés, et
        nous devrions probablement faire office de LiveCD officiel à
        ce projet, tout en gardant néanmoins l'approche embarquée et
        automatisée que nous suivons depuis le commencement du projet.
        Malheureusement, la taille de l'ISO a radicalement augmentée
        (passant maintenant à plus de 20 Mo), tout comme l'utilisation
        mémoire (128 Mo constituant désormais un minimum vital). Mais,
        s'agissant d'une version de développement, ne prenez pas les
        choses de manière trop sérieuse, beaucoup de choses évolueront
        encore d'ici la version finale. Si vous désirez tester cette
        version de démonstration, il ne vous reste qu'à télécharger
        l'ISO <use name="sherkhan_release_20061231"/> et à la graver
        sur un CD ou à l'essayer via VMware ou autre. N'y cherchez pas
        de générateur d'ISO ou à l'installer sur disque, cette version
        n'est pas encore prête pour cela. N'attendez pas non plus à
        avoir un système 100% fonctionnel, il est encore plein de bugs
        et ne fonctionne que depuis une petite semaine ;-) N'y voyez
        donc pas un remplaçant à votre version 1.x courante. A l'heure
        actuelle, l'interface ne peut être contrôlée que par le biais
        du clavier (via les touches Entrée/Echap et les touches
        directionnelles) mais devrait vous permettre de visualiser des
        vidéos, écouter de la musique ou encore d'afficher différents
        formats d'images. Ceci dit, voici quelques captures d'écrans
        pour vous appâter et vous laisser entrevoir la GeeXboX version
        2007 ;-)<br/>
        <br/>
        <use name="scr-freevo"/>
        <br/>
        Sur ce, l'ensemble des membres de l'équipe GeeXboX vous
        souhaite une excellente nouvelle année ...
      </content>
    </subsection>

    <subsection label="release_1.0" date="2006-06-22">
      <content lang="en" title="GeeXboX 1.0: 'As foretold by Nostradamus' edition (posted by Ben)">
      Here we finally are ... after more than 3 years of perpetual development, GeeXboX finally reaches its so long awaited 1.0 release. Many of you were waiting for it and this is probably the best edition of GeeXboX that you've ever had. We've spent so much time in the last few months to fix all the bugs that we can, so that you'll be forced to enjoy it ;-) At the time Aurel and myself started working on GeeXboX, none of us would have expected our software to become that famous. I'm really glad that this version finally came out and I really really want to thank from the depths of my heart all the people of our development team who are getting involved in GeeXboX everyday. None of this would ever have been possible without the work you've all done on it. I'd also like to thank all users that trusted us and are now using our software in a daily manner. You are the ones who made it possible. So for now, I hope you'll all enjoy our 1.0 release, we all did our very best on it, and we're on the road to 2.0.<br/>
      <br/>
      So, what can you expect from this final 1.0 release ? Well, so many things have changed, been added or simply fixed. The most noticeable thing probably is the support for DVD menus, this feature that had been requested so many times by so many people and that was unfortunately missing from MPlayer is now part of GeeXboX. A lot of work also has been done for playing back network streams from SHOUTcast WebRadios, WebTVs or even RTP/RTSP streaming so that you should now be able to easily watch any kind of network or broadcasted stream from your GeeXboX media center. The overall hardware support for various DVB cards, sound cards and video display adapters has also been improved. You're now also able to see all metadata information and properties (like Codecs, resolution or ID3 tags) from your multimedia files. The easiest way to tell you the changes is probably for you to read the concise version of our changelog.<br/>
      <br/>
<b>Detailed Changelog (relative to 0.98.7 release) :</b><br/>
<br/>
<b>System:</b><br/>
- Updated linux to version 2.6.16.17.<br/>
- Updated BusyBox to 1.1.3.<br/>
- Updated uClibc to 2006.05.05 snapshot.<br/>
- Updated udev to version 0.92.<br/>
<br/>
<b>Toolchain:</b><br/>
- Introduced GCC 4.1.1 as the new compiler.<br/>
- Support for C++ in the toolchain.<br/>
- All packages are now built with big files support flag.<br/>
- Added support for non-free binary firmwares at sources build.<br/>
<br/>
<b>Player:</b><br/>
- Updated MPlayer to 1.0pre8.<br/>
- DVD Navigation Menus support.<br/>
- SHOUTcast and Netstream support (with content filtering on adult/subscription-only streams).<br/>
- Support for LIVE555 library (RTP/RTSP/SIP streaming) which provides FreeboxTV support for French people using the Free ISP.<br/>
- Use mp3-lib instead of FFMpeg to avoid audible glitches while seeking.<br/>
- Fix MPlayer's bug which prevents AVI files with ODML index (99% of XviD files) to be read when idx=yes (default).<br/>
- Fix sound/subtitles issues while playing MPEG-TS streams.<br/>
- Support for multichannel AAC in MOV files.<br/>
- Playback of IFO files (DVD disc ripped on HDD for example) now works as expected.<br/>
- Set minimal cache size (5% of cache) to start playback of file very quickly.<br/>
- Fix TV channel OSD name generation with spaces in their name.<br/>
- Allows RTSP client's port forcing (for FreeboxTV users in router mode for example).<br/>
- Added support for DVD-RAM MPEG files.<br/>
<br/>
<b>Menu:</b><br/>
- Brand new menu item selection display (now with alpha layer).<br/>
- Added new menu that displays streams A/V properties.<br/>
- Allows metadata retrieval from MP3/OGG/FLAC audio files.<br/>
- Properties menu auto-opens and updates on audio-only media.<br/>
- Prevent user from browsing (and getting lost) in /<br/>
- Display NIC's MAC address into information menu.<br/>
- Display CDROM size.<br/>
- Fixed display of disks partition size and freespace.<br/>
- Added release number information.<br/>
<br/>
<b>Audio:</b><br/>
- Update ALSA library and utilities to version v1.0.11.<br/>
- Added a lot of fixes for audio playback.<br/>
<br/>
<b>Video:</b><br/>
- Added support for different resolutions to be used through generator.<br/>
- Support for VESA with Intel i865, i910 and i915 chipsets.<br/>
<br/>
<b>Drivers:</b><br/>
- Added support for Serial ATA CDROM drives.<br/>
- Added support for ATAPI/IDE ZIP/LS120 drives.<br/>
- Added support for PcCard (32bits CardBus only, not 16bits PCMCIA).<br/>
- Added LCD displays support through LCD4Linux.<br/>
- Added support for most of the Gigabit NICs.<br/>
- Fix support of Nova DVB-S+ card.<br/>
- Updated LIRC to v0.8.0.<br/>
- Updated rt2400/rt2500 drivers to CVS 05.09.2006.<br/>
- Fix em8300 driver and firmware loading issues.<br/>
<br/>
<b>Networking:</b><br/>
- Updated djmount to version 0.53 (files are no more represented as playlist).<br/>
- Fixed bftpd FTP server write access error.<br/>
- Updated bftpd to version 1.4, and included fix for file transfers greater than 2GB.<br/>
- Update wireless tools to version 28.<br/>
<br/>
<b>Generator:</b><br/>
- Updated generator tools for MacOS X (support for MacIntel x86 OSX 10.4).<br/>
- Allow you to choose between multiple themes.<br/>
- Option for DVD Navigation menus to select it as a default or not.<br/>
- Option for autoplay to select it as a default or not.<br/>
- Option for SHOUTcast (radio and tv netstreams).<br/>
- Tab for video settings configuration (resolution, color depth and boot splash)<br/>
- Tab for support of LCD displays.<br/>
<br/>
<b>Miscellaneous:</b><br/>
- Fixed zoomed scrolling in FBI image viewer.<br/>
- Support for Microsoft Media Center Edition USB, StreamZap, Twinhan DTV, Toshiba VT76F and ATI Remote Wonder II remotes.<br/>
- Implemented full Digimatrix hardware support (apart from panel buttons).<br/>
- Allow multiple resolutions in themes.<br/>
- Support for VMware and QEMU (usefull for test purpose).<br/>
<br/>
      GeeXboX 1.0 is available <a href="downloads.html">here</a> and right now!
      </content>
      <content lang="fr" title="GeeXboX 1.0: 'As foretold by Nostradamus' edition (posté par Ben)">
      Nous voici enfin arrivés à ce jour tant attendu ... après plus de 3 années de développement continu, la GeeXboX a finalement atteint sa version tant attendue, estampillée 1.0. Nombreux d'entre vous l'attendaient et il s'agit très probablement de la version la plus aboutie qu'il vous aura été donné de voir. Nous avons dépensé une telle énergie au cours des derniers mois à corriger les derniers bugs que vous serez forcés d'apprécier cette version ;-) Lorsque Aurelien et moi-même avons débutés l'aventure GeeXboX il y a quelques années, aucun de nous deux n'aurait pu s'attendre à une telle reconnaissance de notre produit et à une telle renommée. Je suis réellement heureux que cette version 1.0 ait finalement vue le jour et je souhaite réellement de tout mon coeur, remercier l'ensemble de notre équipe de développement, toutes ces personnes qui nous ont rejoint et fournissent tant d'efforts chaque jour pour maintenir la qualité de cette distribution. Rien de ce qu'il existe aujourd'hui n'aurait été rendu possible sans la participation de toutes ces personnes. J'aimerai également remercier tous les utilisateurs, qui nous ont soutenu et ont cru en nous depuis si longtemps et qui utilisent désormais la GeeXboX de manière quotidienne. C'est aussi grâce à vous que nous en sommes là aujourd'hui. Pour l'heure, j'espère que vous apprécierez tous cette version 1.0, nous avons réellement donné le meilleur de nous-mêmes et, en route pour la version 2.0 ;-)<br/>
      <br/>
      Revenons en à l'essentiel. Que pouvez vous attendre de cette version 1.0 ? Tellement de choses ont changé, été ajoutées ou tout simplement corrigées depuis la désormais désuette version 0.98.7 ... La fonctionnalité qui vous sautera aux yeux en premier sera sans nul doute le support des menus DVD, cette fonctionnalité qui a été attendue par tous depuis tellement longtemps et qui fait défaut à MPlayer, est désormais incluse dans la GeeXboX. Il s'agit donc là de la première version pré-compilée de MPlayer a proposer cette fonctionnalité. Beaucoup d'efforts ont également été apportés sur la gestion et lecture des flux réseaux tels que les WebRadios et WebTVs par le biais de SHOUTcast ou encore le support du streaming par RTP/RTSP qui devrait vous permettre de lire très facilement tout type de contenu broadcasté à destination de votre media center GeeXboX. Le support matériel a également été amélioré, avec la prise en charge de nombreux nouveaux adaptateurs DVB, cartes sons ou cartes vidéos. Il vous également désormais possible d'extraire les propriétés et informations contenues dans vos fichiers multimédias (comme le type de codec utilisé, la résolution ou encore les tags ID3). Mais le plus simple reste encore de lire ce rapide descriptif des changements apportés :<br/>
      <br/>
<b>Liste détaillée des modifications (depuis la version 0.98.7) : </b><br/>
<br/>
<b>Composants systèmes :</b><br/>
- Mise à jour du noyau Linux en version 2.6.16.17.<br/>
- Mise à jour de BusyBox en version 1.1.3.<br/>
- Mise à jour de la uClibc vers la version de développement du 2006.05.05.<br/>
- Mise à jour de udev en version 0.92.<br/>
<br/>
<b>Chaîne de compilation :</b><br/>
- Introduction de GCC 4.1.1 comme nouveau compilateur.<br/>
- Support du C++ au sein de la chaîne de compilation.<br/>
- L'ensemble des paquetages est désormais compilé avec support des fichiers de plus de 2 Go.<br/>
- Ajout du support pour les firmwares binaires non-libres au sein de la chaîne de compilation.<br/>
<br/>
<b>Lecteur multimédia :</b><br/>
- Mise à jour de MPlayer vers la version 1.0pre8.<br/>
- Support des menus de navigation DVD.<br/>
- Support des contenus réseaux et SHOUTcast (avec filtrage de contenu parental ou pour adultes seulement).<br/>
- Support de la librairie LIVE555 (streaming de contenu RTP/RTSP/SIP) qui permet par exemple la lecture des flux FreeboxTV du FAI français Free.<br/>
- Utilisation de la librairie mp3-lib à la place de FFMpeg pour éviter les effets de saut de son lors de déplacement dans le flux audio ou vidéo (seeking).<br/>
- Correction d'un bug dans MPlayer qui empêchait la lecture des fichiers avec index OpenDML (99% des fichiers XviD) lorsque le paramètre idx=yes était activé (defaut).<br/>
- Correction des problèmes de son et sous-titres lors de la lecture de flux MPEG-TS (DVB par exemple).<br/>
- Support du son multicanaux AAC au sein des fichiers MOV.<br/>
- Le support de la lecture des fichiers IFO (i.e un disque DVD copié sur disque dur par exemple) fonctionne désormais de manière correcte.<br/>
- Activation de la taille minimale du cache (à 5% de la valeur totale du cache) afin de permettre le démarrage plus rapide des fichiers.<br/>
- Correction d'un bug dans la génération des noms de chaînes TV qui contenaient un espace dans leur nom.<br/>
- Permet à l'utilisateur de fixer le port RTSP sur lequel les contenus devront être envoyés (pour les utilisateurs FreeboxTV fonctionnant en mode routeur par exemple).<br/>
- Support des fichiers MPEG DVD-RAM.<br/>
<br/>
<b>Menu OSD :</b><br/>
- Nouveau menu de séléction (avec support du canal alpha de transparence).<br/>
- Ajout d'un nouveau menu permettant de visualiser les propriétés audio/vidéo d'un flux.<br/>
- Allows metadata retrieval from MP3/OGG/FLAC audio files.<br/>
- Le menu des propriétés du fichier s'ouvre automatiquement lors de la lecture de contenus audio uniquement.<br/>
- Ajout d'une protection empêchant l'utilisateur d'aller dans le répertoire / (et de s'y perdre), en considérant le point de montage des disques (locaux et réseaux) comme point central.<br/>
- Affichage de l'addresse MAC de la carte réseau au sein du menu d'informations systèmes.<br/>
- Affichage de l'espace disque consommé par le CDROM.<br/>
- Correction du bug d'affichage des valeurs d'espace disque libre et occupé pour les partitions des disques.<br/>
- Ajout de l'affichage dans le menu du numéro de version de la GeeXboX.<br/>
<br/>
<b>Audio :</b><br/>
- Mise à jour de la librairie ALSA et de ses utilitaires en version v1.0.11.<br/>
- Correction de nombreux problèmes de lecture audio.<br/>
<br/>
<b>Vidéo :</b><br/>
- Ajout du support de multiples résolutions par le biais du générateur.<br/>
- Support VESA des chipsets Intel i865, i910 et i915.<br/>
<br/>
<b>Pilotes :</b><br/>
- Support des lecteurs de CDROM au format Serial ATA.<br/>
- Support des lecteurs ATAPI/IDE ZIP/LS120.<br/>
- Support (tant attendu) des cartes d'extensions PcCard (CardBus en mode 32bits uniquement, les anciennes cartes PCMCIA 16bits ne sont toujours pas supportées).<br/>
- Support des écrans d'affichage LCD au travers de LCD4Linux.<br/>
- Support de nombreuses cartes réseau Gigabit.<br/>
- Support étendu de la carte Nova DVB-S+.<br/>
- Mise à jour de LIRC en version v0.8.0.<br/>
- Mise à jour des pilotes rt2400/rt2500 vers la version CVS 05.09.2006.<br/>
- Correction des problèmes de chargement de firmware pour le pilote em8300 (cartes RealMagic Hollywood+).<br/>
<br/>
<b>Réseau :</b><br/>
- Mise à jour de djmount en version 0.53 (les fichiers ne sont désormais plus vus comme des listes de lecture).<br/>
- Correction du problème d'accès en écriture du serveur FTP bftpd.<br/>
- Mise à jour du serveur bftpd en version 1.4, permettant le transfert de fichiers supérieurs à 2 Go.<br/>
- Mise à jour des wireless tools vers la version 28.<br/>
<br/>
<b>Générateur :</b><br/>
- Mise à jour du générateur pour MacOS X (support pour les MacIntel x86 sous OSX 10.4).<br/>
- Permet le choix entre différents thèmes de démarrage et de menu.<br/>
- Ajout d'une option permettant l'activation ou non par défaut du menu de navigation DVD.<br/>
- Ajout d'une option permettant l'activation ou non par défaut de la fonctionnalité de démarrage automatique des contenus sur CD.<br/>
- Nouvel onglet de configuration des flux réseaux et SHOUTcast (radio et TV).<br/>
- Nouvel onglet de configuration des paramètres vidéo (résolution, profondeur de couleur et écran de démarrage).<br/>
- Nouvel onglet de configuration et d'activation des écrans LCD.<br/>
<br/>
<b>Divers :</b><br/>
- Correction des problèmes de zooms et de déplacements au sein du visauliseur d'images FBI.<br/>
- Support des télécommandes Microsoft Media Center Edition USB, StreamZap, Twinhan DTV, Toshiba VT76F et ATI Remote Wonder II.<br/>
- Support complet du barebone ASUS Digimatrix (excepté les boutons frontaux).<br/>
- Permet le choix entre de multiples résolutions pour les thèmes.<br/>
- Support de la virtualisation via VMware et QEMU (très utile dans un contexte de développement).<br/>
<br/>
      La GeeXboX 1.0 est disponible dès à présent sur notre <a href="downloads.html">page de téléchargements</a>.
      </content>
      <content lang="de" title="GeeXboX 1.0: 'As foretold by Nostradamus' edition (posted by Ben)">
      Here we finally are ... after more than 3 years of perpetual development, GeeXboX finally reaches its so long waited for 1.0 release number. Many of you were waiting for it and this is probably the best edition of GeeXboX you'll ever had. We've spent so much time in the last few monthes to fix the most bugs we can that you'll be forced to enjoy it ;-) At the time Aurel and myself started working on GeeXboX, none of us would have expected our software to become that famous. I'm really glad that this version finally came out and I really really want to thank from the deepest of my heart all the people of our development  team who is getting involved in GeeXboX everyday. None of this would ever have been possible without the work you've all done on it. I'd also like to thank all users that trusted us and are now using our software in a daily manner. You are the ones who made it possible. So for now, I hope you'll all enjoy our 1.0 release, we all did our very best and let's road to 2.0.<br/>
      <br/>
      So, what can you expect from this final 1.0 release ? Well, so many things have changed, been added or simply fixed. The most noticeable thing probably is the support for DVD menus, this feature that has been asked for so many people for so many times and that was unfortunately missing from MPlayer is now part of GeeXboX. A lot of work also has been done for playing back network streams from SHOUTcast WebRadios, WebTVs or even RTP/RTSP streaming that you should now be able to easily watch any kind of network or broadcasted stream from your GeeXboX media center. The overall hardware support for various DVB cards, sound cards and video display adapters also has been improved. You're now also able to see all metadata information and properties (like Codecs, resolution or ID3 tags) from your multimedia files. But the easier probably is for you to read out our shortened changelog.<br/>
      <br/>
<b>Detailed Changelog (relative to 0.98.7 release) :</b><br/>
<br/>
<b>System:</b><br/>
- Updated linux to version 2.6.16.17.<br/>
- Updated BusyBox to 1.1.3.<br/>
- Updated uClibc to 2006.05.05 snapshot.<br/>
- Updated udev to version 0.92.<br/>
<br/>
<b>Toolchain:</b><br/>
- Introduced GCC 4.1.1 as the new compiler.<br/>
- Support for C++ in the toolchain.<br/>
- All packages are now built with big files support flag.<br/>
- Added support for non-free binary firmwares at sources build.<br/>
<br/>
<b>Player:</b><br/>
- Updated MPlayer to 1.0pre8.<br/>
- DVD Navigation Menus support.<br/>
- SHOUTcast and Netstream support (with content filtering on adult/subscription-only streams).<br/>
- Support for LIVE555 library (RTP/RTSP/SIP streaming) which provides FreeboxTV support for French people using the Free ISP.<br/>
- Use mp3-lib instead of FFMpeg to avoid audible glitches while seeking.<br/>
- Fix MPlayer's bug which prevents AVI files with ODML index (99% of XviD files) to be read when idx=yes (default).<br/>
- Fix sound/subtitles issues while playing MPEG-TS streams.<br/>
- Support for multichannel AAC in MOV files.<br/>
- Playback of IFO files (DVD disc ripped on HDD for example) now works as expected.<br/>
- Set minimal cache size (5% of cache) to start playback of file very quickly.<br/>
- Fixes on TV channels generation with spaces in their name.<br/>
- Allows RTSP client's port forcing (for FreeboxTV users in router mode for example).<br/>
- Added support for DVD-RAM MPEG files.<br/>
<br/>
<b>Menu:</b><br/>
- Brand new menu item selection display (now with alpha layer).<br/>
- Added new menu that displays streams A/V properties.<br/>
- Allows metadata retrieval from MP3/OGG/FLAC audio files.<br/>
- Properties menu auto-opens and updates on audio-only media.<br/>
- Prevent user from browsing (and getting lost) in /<br/>
- Display NIC's MAC address into information menu.<br/>
- Display CDROM size.<br/>
- Fixed display of disks partition size and freespace.<br/>
- Added release number information.<br/>
<br/>
<b>Audio:</b><br/>
- Update ALSA library and utilities to version v1.0.11.<br/>
- Added a lot of fixes for audio playback.<br/>
<br/>
<b>Video:</b><br/>
- Added support for different resolutions to be used through generator.<br/>
- Support for VESA with Intel i865, i910 and i915 chipsets.<br/>
<br/>
<b>Drivers:</b><br/>
- Added support for Serial ATA CDROM drives.<br/>
- Added support for ATAPI/IDE ZIP/LS120 drives.<br/>
- Added support for PcCard (32bits CardBus only, not 16bits PCMCIA).<br/>
- Added LCD displays support through LCD4Linux.<br/>
- Added support for most of Gigabit NICs.<br/>
- Fix support of Nova DVB-S+ card.<br/>
- Updated LIRC to v0.8.0.<br/>
- Updated rt2400/rt2500 drivers to CVS 05.09.2006.<br/>
- Fix em8300 driver and firmware loading issues.<br/>
<br/>
<b>Networking:</b><br/>
- Updated djmount to version 0.53 (files are no more represented as playlist).<br/>
- Fixed bftpd FTP server write access error.<br/>
- Updated bftpd to version 1.4, and included fix for file transfers greater than 2GB.<br/>
- Update wireless tools to version 28.<br/>
<br/>
<b>Generator:</b><br/>
- Updated generator tools for MacOS X (support for MacIntel x86 OSX 10.4).<br/>
- Allow you to choose between multiple themes.<br/>
- Tab for DVD Navigation menus tab to select it as a default or not.<br/>
- Tab for autoplay tab to select it as a default or not.<br/>
- Tab for SHOUTcast (radio and tv netstreams).<br/>
- Tab for video settings configuration (resolution, color depth and boot splash)<br/>
- Tab for support of LCD displays.<br/>
<br/>
<b>Miscellaneous:</b><br/>
- Fix zoomed scrolling in FBI image viewer.<br/>
- Support for Microsoft Media Center Edition USB, StreamZap, Twinhan DTV, Toshiba VT76F and ATI Remote Wonder II remotes.<br/>
- Implemented full Digimatrix hardware support.<br/>
- Allow multiple resolutions in themes.<br/>
- Support for VMware and QEMU (usefull for test purpose).<br/>
<br/>
      GeeXboX 1.0 is available <a href="downloads.html">here</a> and right now!
      </content>
    </subsection>

  </section>
</article>
