<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<!DOCTYPE article SYSTEM "geexbox.dtd">

<article>
  <define name="mozilla">
    <a href="http://www.mozilla.org/">Mozilla</a>
  </define>
  <define name="freshmeat">
    <a href="http://freshmeat.net/projects/geexbox/"><i>Freshmeat</i></a>  
  </define>
  <define name="drafts">
    <a href="../drafts/">page</a>
  </define>          
  <define name="devel">
    <a href="../releases/devel/pre-0.99/">page</a>
  </define>          

  <section label="news">
    <content lang="en" title="Latest News ..."/>
    <content lang="fr" title="Dernières Nouvelles ..."/>

    <subsection label="pre_0.99">
      <content lang="en" title="Help with GeeXboX development : try devel releases">    
        Almost 2 months have passed since GeeXboX 0.98 was released. Lots of work has been done since then. For example, we're now supporting the Linux 2.6 kernel series and many improvements have been made to the video output. It now fully supports the VESA 3.0 specification, adding a new support for all 3Dfx and Intel i845/i855/i865 cards and chipsets. Also, pictures are now rendered using 24 bit depth.<br/><br/>

        We're now almost finished with the architecture changes we've planned to do for 0.99 release, and we can finally start to work on a complete rework of the menu interface. To give you a taste of the future of GeeXboX, you can simply have a look at our <i>Work In Progress</i><use name="drafts"/>. Currently it's only a snapshot of the coming 0.99 and to provide you with such a perfect release as soon as possible, we need you to test our development release and report to us as many bugs as possible.<br/><br/>

        We'll try to release as many development versions as we can. In each release we would add significant changes. So, if you want to help us, please try our development release here <use name="devel"/>. Please understand that they are snapshots of a work in progress, meaning that they can not be considered as stable. If you want to be sure to use a stable release, keep using the 0.98 release.
      </content>
      <content lang="fr" title="Contribuer au développement de la GeeXboX : testez les versions de développements.">    
        Presque 2 mois se sont écoulés depuis la sortie de la version 0.98 de la GeeXboX. De nombreuses améliorations ont été apportées depuis et, pour ne citer que les principales, la distribution supporte désormais la série 2.6 du noyau Linux et de gros efforts ont été portés sur l'amélioration de la qualité d'affichage. La GeeXboX supporte désormais une profondeur de rendu d'image de 24 bits et respecte les spécifications de la norme VESA 3.0, ce qui nous permet (enfin) de supporter les cartes graphiques et chipsets 3Dfx et Intel i845/i855/i865.<br/><br/>

        Nous en avons maintenant quasiment fini avec les changements d'architecture que nous avions prévu d'apporter à la future version 0.99 et nous sommes désormais en mesure de concentrer nos efforts sur une refonte complète de l'interface du menu. Pour vous donner un aperçu du futur de la GeeXboX, vous pouvez simplement jetter un oeil sur notre page <use name="drafts"/> d'ébauche de l'interface. A l'heure actuelle il ne s'agit que d'un simple aperçu de la future version 0.99 et, afin de la distribuer au plus tôt, nous avons besoin de votre aide pour tester nos versions de développement et pour nous rapporter tous les bugs que vous pourrez rencontrer.<br/><br/>

        Nous essaierons de mettre à votre disposition de nouvelles versions de développement aussi souvent que possible, dès que des changements significatifs auront été apportés. Ainsi, si vous souhaitez contribuer au développement, vous êtes invités à tester nos versions de développement sur cette <use name="devel"/>. Comprenez bien cependant qu'il ne s'agit que de versions unstables, en cours de développement, et qui ne peuvent être considérées comme stable. Si vous souhaitez utiliser une version certifiée stable de la GeeXboX, la 0.98 est faite pour vous.
      </content>
    </subsection>

    <subsection label="release_0.98">
      <content lang="en" title="GeeXboX 0.98 (08/12/04)">
      Here comes the GeeXboX again. This 0.98 edition is a key point in our roadmap. This does not really come with many new features (or some new useful things) but fixes a huge number of annoying bugs. Most of all, this release will probably be the last time you see GeeXboX in its current state. We have plans to work harder than ever to bring you new OS, like you've never seen, still keeping it as simple to use as it ever been. So just stay tuned :-)<br/><br/>
      Ok, back from the future, lets give you details about the current release. Here's what you've been waiting for : <br/><br/>
* Switch MPlayer to 1.0pre5<br/>
* Fix for key delay with ATI Remote Wonder.<br/>
* Better WiFi support and drivers for RT2400 and ACX100 chipsets.<br/>
* Better support for FTP file transfer.<br/>
* Disk free space information is now available in the menu.<br/>
* Added player control through joysticks (all USB models and Microsoft SideWinder on traditional gameport).<br/>
* Added support for SPDIF (digital) sound output.<br/>
* Better support of WideScreen (16:9) displays and fix the TV-Out norm (PAL/NTSC) with DXR3 cards.<br/>
* Added support for software decoding of DTS audio streams.<br/>
* Autodetection and autoplay of the the longest available DVD title (should be the right one, i.e. the one containing the main movie).<br/>
* Added a GeeXboX's generator Debian's package building script.<br/>
* Fixed some compilation compatibility issues with distributions other than Debian (i.e. should work pretty well under Mandrake 10 and Fedora Core 2).<br/>
* Added a chapter selector for DVDs and Matroska files.<br/>
* Fix the TV-Out problem with nVidia cards : display should no more turn to black-and-white at each video change.<br/>
* The generator now includes a distinction between the receiver and the remote itself.<br/>
* Added support for external USB SmartMedia and CompactFlash cards readers.<br/><br/>
      Hope you'll be pleased with this release, 'cause the next one will kick-ass :-) By the way, we're still lacking support in several areas. More than ever, we need translators, designers, and documentation updaters. If you get some free time and want to help us, please let us know. Oh, and if you really like GeeXboX and want to be warned each time a new version is released, you can freely subscribe to our project page on <use name="freshmeat"/>(and let us gain some popularity at the same time, maybe one day we'll rank at the top :-)<br/>
      </content>
      <content lang="fr" title="GeeXboX 0.98 (12/08/04)">
      Et voici débarquer la nouvelle GeeXboX en cette période estivale. Cette version 0.98 marque un point clé dans notre développement. En effet, cette dernière ne contient pas de réelles avancées (bien que vous y retrouverez quelques petites nouveautés bien utiles) mais plutot un très grand nombre de corrections de bugs. Mais surtout, cette version 0.98 sera très probablement la dernière fois que vous verrez la GeeXboX sous son apparence actuelle. Nous avons prévu de travailler plus dur que jamais pour vous fournir un nouvel OS, comme vous ne l'aurez jamais vu, tout en gardant sa simplicité d'utilisation actuelle. Restez donc à l'écoute :-)<br/><br/>
      Ok, revenons sur terre, voici donc les détails concernant la version actuelle. Voici donc ce pour quoi vous avez tant attendu : <br/><br/>
* Passage à MPlayer 1.0pre5<br/>
* Correction de la temporisation des touches de l'ATI Remote Wonder.<br/>
* Meilleur support du WiFi et ajout des drivers pour chipsets RT2400 et ACX100.<br/>
* Meilleur support des transferts de fichier via FTP.<br/>
* L'information sur l'espace disque disponible est désormais accessible via le menu.<br/>
* Le lecteur est désormais controlable via un joystick (sont supportés, tous les modèles USB ainsi que les Microsoft SideWinder sur port de jeu traditionnel).<br/>
* Ajout du support de la sortie numérique SPDIF des cartes sons.<br/>
* Meilleur support des écrans panoramiques (16:9) et possibilité de choisir la norme d'affichage (PAL/NTSC) avec les cartes DXR3.<br/>
* Support du décodage logiciel des flux audio au format DTS.<br/>
* Autodétection et lecture automatique du plus long titre d'un DVD (ce qui devrait correspondre à celui contenant le film principal).<br/>
* Ajout d'un script permettant de générer un package Debian du générateur d'ISO.<br/>
* Correction d'un problème de compatibilité à la compilation des sources avec des distributions autres que Debian (i.e. cela devrait fonctionner à merveille avec une Mandrake 10 et/ou Fedora Core 2).<br/>
* Ajout d'un menu de sélection des chapitres pour les DVDs et fichiers Matroska.<br/>
* Correction du problème de sortie TV avec les cartes nVidia : l'affichage ne devrait maintenant plus rebasculer en Noir et Blanc à chaque changement de vidéo.<br/>
* Le générateur d'ISO inclut désormais une distinction entre le récepteur de la télécommande et la télécommande elle-meme.<br/>
* Ajout du support des lecteurs USB externes de cartes SmartMedia et CompactFlash.<br/><br/>
      Nous espérons que cette version 0.98 vous plaira, car la prochaine sera décoiffante :-) A ce propos, nous avons encore et toujours besoin de support dans de nombreux domaines. Plus que jamais, nous avons besoin de traducteurs, documentalistes, graphistes et designers. Si vous avez du temps à disposition et souhaitez nous aider, faites nous le savoir. Et, pour conclure, si vous appréciez la GeeXboX et souhaitez etre informés par mail dès qu'une nouvelle version est disponible au grand public, vous pouvez vous enregistrer sur la page de notre projet sur <use name="freshmeat"/>(et par là meme, nous permettre de gagner et popularité et, pourquoi pas arriver un jour en haut de la liste :-)<br/>
      </content>
    </subsection>

    <subsection label="release_0.97">
      <content lang="en" title="GeeXboX 0.97 : Birthday Edition (05/16/04)">
      'I think it was the hardest version to release but 0.97 has finally come, exactly one year after the first public release. As you may have noticed, our website was unreachable for some time in the last month and until only recently, some services were unfortunately down. Let's clarify the situation. Our previous host (<a href="http://www.tuxfamily.org/"><i>tuxfamily.org</i></a>) has been attacked by hackers in January 2004 and decided to stop hosting free projects for an undefined period. Thanks to <b>BWare</b>, a member of the GeeXboX's forum, we got the opportunity to get a nearly dedicated web server with lots of bandwidth. Many thanks to him, without whom our services wouldn't have been restored at this time. More than ever, we need generous contributors and donators to help the project and prevent us from such a situation to happen once again. If you believe in our project, don't hesitate to have a look at the appropriate section of this website.<br/><br/>
Let's stop with it, it's now time to talk about the 0.97 release :-) For many reasons (like the one just above), the developement took really much more time that we could have wished. But you will be glad to know that this release comes with many new features that have been requested by users for a long time. By the way, one of the longest period between releases is the bug tracking phase. We often release developement versions of GeeXboX and you're all welcomed to test them the most you can. Please remember that the most you are to test and to report bugs and the quicker will new versions be released.<br/><br/>
So, as usual, here's a quick changelog of the new features for which you've been waiting for so long : <br/><br/>
* Switch MPlayer to 1.0pre4<br/>
* Support for Packard Bell Fast media remote and receiver.<br/>
* Support for DXR3/Hollywood+ (MPEG1/2 hardware decoder) cards (TVOut only for now).<br/>
* Support for S3 Virge GX2 TV Out.<br/>
* Support for the Matroska container.<br/>
* Support for the Nullsoft streaming video (NSV) container.<br/>
* Support for PCI and USB WiFi network adapters (AiroNet, Atmel, and Prism2 chipsets).<br/>
* Support for Serial ATA disks.<br/>
* Support for 3COM/NetGear Gigabit ethernet cards.<br/>
* Support for BT8x8 and Saa73134 cards (Composite and S-VHS inputs and TV tuners).<br/>
* Support for audio/video streaming (Web-Radios etc ...)<br/>
* Access to the Internet through web gateways.<br/>
* Added Telnet server for remote access.<br/>
* Support for hardware video acceleration (VidiX) for EPIA-M (CLE266 chipset) and ATI Radeon 9xxx boards.<br/>
* Support for VidiX for nVidia cards (EXPERIMENTAL : disabled by defaut).<br/>
* Added the IrMan library.<br/>
* Support for ATI Remote Wonder remotes through LIRC (better latency time and customizable key bindings).<br/>
* Added an image viewer (FBI) with support for BMP, GIF, JPEG, PCD, PNG, PNM and PPM formats.<br/>
* Switch from CVS revision control system to GNU Arch.<br/>
      </content>
      <content lang="fr" title="GeeXboX 0.97 : Birthday Edition (16/05/04)">
      Cela a du être la version la plus difficile à sortir, mais la version 0.97 a finalement vu le jour, exactement 1 an après la première version publique de la GeeXboX. Comme vous aurez pu le remarquer, notre site web fut inaccesible pendant quelques jours depuis la fin Janvier et, jusqu'à présent, certains services étaient inaccessibles. Tentons de clarifier la situation. Notre hôte précédent (<a href="http://www.tuxfamily.org/"><i>tuxfamily.org</i></a>) a subit des attaques de pirates en Janvier 2004 et a malheureusement décidé de stoper l'hébergement de projets libres pour un temps indéfini. De grands mercis à <b>BWare</b>, un membre du forum GeeXboX, qui nous a fourni un serveur quasi-dédié ainsi que la bande passante nécessaire. Nous le remercions encore car, sans lui, nos services n'auraient peut être pas encore pu redémarrer. Plus que jamais, nous avons besoin de généreux contributeurs et/ou donateurs au projet pour empêcher qu'une telle situation ne se reproduise. Si vous croyez en ce projet, n'hésitez pas à jetter un oeil à la section apropprié du site.<br/><br/>
Arrêtons un peu tout cela, pour reparler de la version 0.97 de la GeeXboX :-) Pour de nombreuses raisons (comme celle présentée ci-dessus), le développement a pris bien plus de temps que nous l'avions prévu. Mais vous serez heureux d'apprendre que cette version arrive avec de nombreuses fonctionnalités que vous attendiez depuis un long moment. Par ailleurs, une des phases les plus longues entre 2 nouvelles versions est bien évidemment la chasse aux bugs. Nous sortons fréquemment des versions de développement de la GeeXboX et vous êtes tous cordialement invités à les tester le plus qu'il vous est possible de le faire. Ayez à l'esprit que plus vous serez à tester et rapporter les bugs et plus rapidement sortira chaque nouvelle version.<br/><br/>
Donc, comme à l'accoutumée, voici un rapide aperçu des nouvelles fonctionnalités pour lesquelles vous avez tant attendu : <br/><br/>
* Passage à MPlayer 1.0pre4<br/>
* Support des télécommandes et récépteurs Packard Bell Fast media.<br/>
* Support des cartes DXR3/Hollywood+ (décodeurs MPEG1/2 matériel) (Sortie TV uniquement pour l'instant).<br/>
* Support de la sortie TV des cartes S3 Virge GX2.<br/>
* Support du conteneur audio/vidéo Matroska.<br/>
* Support du conteneur Nullsoft streaming video (NSV).<br/>
* Support des cartes réseaux WiFi aux formats PCI et USB (chipsets AiroNet, Atmel, et Prism2).<br/>
* Support des disques Serial ATA.<br/>
* Support des cartes Ethernet 3COM/NetGear Gigabit.<br/>
* Support des cartes BT8x8 et Saa7134 (entrées Composite et S-VHS et des tuners TV).<br/>
* Support du streaming audio/vidéo (Web-Radios etc ...)<br/>
* Accès à Internet via des passerelles web.<br/>
* Ajout d'un serveur Telnet pour prise en main distante.<br/>
* Support de l'acceleration vidéo matérielle (VidiX) pour les cartes EPIA-M (chipset CLE266) et ATI Radeon 9xxx.<br/>
* Support VidiX pour les cartes nVidia (EXPERIMENTAL : désactivé par défaut).<br/>
* Ajout de la librairie IrMan.<br/>
* Support des télécommandes ATI Remote Wonder via LIRC (temps de réponse amélioré et configuration des touches possibles).<br/>
* Ajout d'un visualiseur d'images (FBI) avec support des formats BMP, GIF, JPEG, PCD, PNG, PNM et PPM.<br/>
* Passage du gestionnaire de version CVS à GNU Arch.<br/>
      </content>
    </subsection>

    <subsection label="site_v2">
      <content lang="en" title="GeeXboX Website updated (01/13/04)">
      OpenWeb's stylesheet was used for too long. OpenWeb's people were not so pleased so we've finally taken the time to redesign it from scratch. You're now even able to switch between two different stylesheets (feel free to submit new ones if you're inspired).<br/><br/>

      As always, the site is W3C standards compliant (XHTML 1.1 and CSS 2). If you notice display problems, just use a CSS 2 compliant browser (for example <use name="mozilla"/>).
      </content>
      <content lang="fr" title="Mise à jour du site GeeXboX (13/01/04)">
      Nous utilisions la feuille de style du consortium OpenWeb depuis trop longtemps. Cela n'enchantait guère les gens d'OpenWeb et nous avons donc enfin pris le temps de créer un nouveau design depuis zéro. Vous pouvez maintenant choisir entre deux thèmes différents (libre à vous de nous en soumettre de nouveaux).<br/><br/>

      Comme d'habitude, le site est conforme aux standards du W3C (XHTML 1.1 et CSS 2). Si vous rencontrez des problèmes d'affichage, utilisez simplement un navigateur respectant ces standards (par exemple <use name="mozilla"/>).
      </content>
    </subsection>

    <subsection label="release_0.96">
      <content lang="en" title="GeeXboX Xmas Edition : 0.96 (12/18/03)">
      It's Christmas time ! So comes the new release, ready to be put under the Xmas tree :-) Most of the changes are essentially bug fixes and added hardware support just to please more and more users. Here's part of the Changelog :<br/><br/>
* New remotes support (this feature was broken in previous release when used with the autoplay function).<br/>
* Switch MPlayer to 1.0pre3 release and ALSA to 1.0rc2.<br/>
* Support for DirectFB video mode.<br/>
* Support for 3Dfx cards.<br/>
* Support for USB devices hotplug.<br/>
* Support for nForce Ethernet controller.<br/>
* Support for NFS shares.<br/>
* Support for Windows 2k/XP multi-boot manager.<br/>
* Support for AniMAX remote.<br/>
* Ready to boot network, using PXE method.<br/>
* Russian font fix.<br/>
* Added bulgarian, romanian, polish and german languages.<br/><br/>
The GeeXboX team also provides you a live IRC chatroom, to share your experience with worldwide users about all yours suggestions or problems. Please connect to IRC server <b>chat.zone-irc.org</b> and join the <b>#geexbox</b> room.<br/><br/>
This release is dedicated to our first generous donator (we're sure he will recognize himself :) for his xmas gift which will help us in further development. Besides, we want to thank you, users from all around the world, for using GeeXboX, we wish you a merry Christmas and hope you will continue using our software next year :-p<br/>
      </content>
      <content lang="fr" title="GeeXboX Xmas Edition : 0.96 (18/12/03)">
      C'est bientôt Noël ! Voici donc la nouvelle version, prête à être posée juste sous le sapin :-) La plupart des changements constituent essentiellement des corrections de bugs ou ajout de support matériel, afin de contenter chaque jour davantage d'utilisateurs. Voici donc la liste de ces ajouts :<br/><br/>
* Télécommandes à nouveau fonctionnelles (cette fonction était devenue inutilisable avec la version précédente, lorsqu'utilisée conjointement à l'autoplay.<br/>
* Passage à MPlayer 1.0pre3 et ALSA 1.0rc2.<br/>
* Support de l'affichage en mode DirectFB.<br/>
* Support des cartes 3Dfx.<br/>
* Support du branchement à chaud (hotplug) pour les périphériques USB.<br/>
* Support du controlleur Ethernet des cartes nForce.<br/>
* Support des partages NFS.<br/>
* Support du multi-boot depuis le chargeur Windows 2000/XP.<br/>
* Support de la télécommande AniMAX.<br/>
* Prêt à booter depuis le réseau, en utilisant la méthode PXE.<br/>
* Correction des polices Russe.<br/>
* Support de nouvelles langues : bulgare, roumain, polonais et allemand.<br/><br/>
L'équipe GeeXboX met également à votre disposition un canal IRC, pour partager votre expérience avec les utilisateurs du monde entier, que ce soit vos suggestions ou vos problèmes. Connectez vous au serveur IRC <b>chat.zone-irc.org</b> sur le canal <b>#geexbox</b>.<br/><br/>
Cette version est dédiée à notre premier généreux donateur (nous sommes convaincus qu'il se reconnaîtra :) pour son cadeau de Noël qui nous aidera beaucoup pour le développement à venir. Nous tenons enfin à vous remercier, tous tant que vous êtes, d'utiliser la GeeXboX et de nous aider à l'améliorer. Toute l'équipe vous souhaite de joyeuses fêtes de fin d'année et espère vous retrouver nombreux en 2004 pour la suite des aventures :-)<br/>
      </content>
    </subsection>

    <subsection label="forum_crash">
      <content lang="en" title="GeeXboX's Forum Crashdown (12/10/03)">
      As you may have noticed, GeeXboX's forum has been unreachable for the last 10 days due to an unknown problem with our PostgreSQL database. A severe error cause our host to completely purge it with, unfortunately, no existing backup :-( This means that the forum has been completely purged. Our sincere apologies for this situation.<br/><br/>
      All existing threads and registrations have been lost, so you just have to register again to the forum (a weekly backup is now automatically done). To make you feel better, we can say that the 0.96 release of GeeXboX is really close to release, so stay tuned :p<br/>
      </content>
      <content lang="fr" title="Crash du Forum GeeXboX (10/12/03)">
      Comme vous avez pu le constater, le forum GeeXboX est resté inaccesible depuis environ 10 jours pour un problème inconnu sur notre base de données PostgreSQL. Une erreur sérieuse a contraint notre hébergeur à procéder à un nettoyage complet de cette dernière, sans malheureusement que nous ayons la moindre sauvegarde :-( Ceci signifie que le forum a été complètement effacé. Toutes nos excuses pour une telle situaion.<br/><br/>
      Tous les messages existants et autres enregistrements ont été perdus, de ce fait vous devrez à nouveau vous inscrire au forum (un processus de sauvegarde automatique hebdomadaire a été mis en place). Pour faire passer le pilule, nous vous annonçons simplement que la sortie de la version 0.96 de la GeeXboX est toute proche, restez à l'écoute :p<br/>
      </content>
    </subsection>

    <subsection label="release_0.95">
      <content lang="en" title="GeeXboX Halloween Edition : 0.95 (10/20/03)">
      Here it comes again ! GeeXboX releases take lots and lots of time but we've added a full list of new features and bug fixes, as usual. In this release, many compatibility problems have been solved and there's the much-awaited support for soundcards with digital output. Look at this quick changelog :<br/><br/>
* Fix display problems with nVidia, SiS and Kyro graphic adapters.<br/>
* Support for multi-subbed OGM files.<br/>
* Added AutoPlay.<br/>
* Added XCD support.<br/>
* Added lots of translations (available in 11 languages).<br/>
* Added support for Creative PC-DVD, Sony RM-S6 and RX-V850 remote controllers.<br/>
* Added a GUI-Win32 version of the generator with many bugfixes.<br/>
* Updated MPlayer to version 1.0pre2.<br/>
* Replace OSS sound drivers by ALSA ones, with support for digital outputs.<br/>
* Set resolution to 800x600 to fix some TV-Out bugs.<br/>
* Fix the DVD playback problem.<br/>
* Upgraded Samba to 3.0 with better WinXP shares support.<br/>
* Better USB keys support and detection.<br/>
* Added FTP server to easily modify GeeXboX's configuration files or copy movies from the network.<br/>
* Native support for QuickTime SVQ3, H264, ASV 1/2, Indeo, ATI VCR 1/2, and 3ivX codecs.<br/> 
* GeeXboX can be booted under Debug mode.<br/>
      </content>
      <content lang="fr" title="GeeXboX Halloween Edition : 0.95 (20/10/03)">
      La GeeXboX est à nouveau de retour ! La durée entre chaque nouvelle version de la GeeXboX s'allonge à chaque fois mais, il en va de même pour la liste des nouvelles fonctionnalités et des bugs corrigés, comme àl'accoutumée. Cette fois, de nombreux problèmes de compatibilité ont été résolus et l'on peut découvrir le support tant attendu pour les sorties numériques de cartes son. Voici donc un rapide descriptif des nouveautés :<br/><br/>
* Correction des problèmes d'affichage avec les cartes graphiques nVidia, SiS et Kyro.<br/>
* Support des fichiers OGM multi sous-titres.<br/>
* Ajout de l'AutoPlay.<br/>
* Support des XCD.<br/>
* Ajout de nombreuses traductions (disponibles dans 11 langues).<br/>
* Support des télécommandes Creative PC-DVD, Sony RM-S6 et RX-V850.<br/>
* Ajout d'une interface graphique pour Win32 du générateur d'ISO avec de nombreux correctifs.<br/>
* Mise à jour de MPlayer vers la version 1.0pre2.<br/>
* Remplacement des drivers son OSS par ceux de ALSA, avec support des sorties numériques.<br/>
* Résolution ajustée à 800x600 avec correction des problèmes de sortie TV.<br/>
* Correction du problème de lecture des DVD.<br/>
* Mise à jour de Samba en version 3.0 avec un meilleur support des partages WinXP.<br/>
* Meilleur support et détection des clés USB.<br/>
* Ajout d'un serveur FTP permettant une modification rapide et facile des fichiers de configuration de la GeeXboX ou pour copier des films depuis le réseau.<br/>
* Support natif des codecs QuickTime SVQ3, H264, ASV 1/2, Indeo, ATI VCR 1/2, et 3ivX.<br/> 
* La GeeXboX peut désormais être démarrée en mode de débogguage.<br/>      
      </content>
    </subsection>

    <subsection label="cd_0.90-4">
      <content lang="en" title="GeeXboX's CD available (08/22/03)">
      For people who don't have a high speed connection to the Internet, the GeeXboX CD is available. This provides you the 0.90-4 bootable release and the full source packages of all GeeXboX releases, for only 1.99$. More information is available at the <page name="download"/> section.
      </content>
      <content lang="fr" title="Disponibilité du CD GeeXboX (22/08/03)">
      Pour ceux qui ne disposeraient pas de connection Internet haut-débit, ils peuvent commander le CD GeeXboX, qui contient la version bootable 0.90-4, ainsi que les sources complètes de toutes les versions, pour la modique somme de 1.99e. Plus de renseignements, dans la section <page name="download"/>.
      </content>
    </subsection>

    <subsection label="release_0.90-4">
      <content lang="en" title="GeeXboX Summer Edition : 0.90-4 (08/05/03)">
        Here is GeeXboX's new release ;-) It now comes with the 2 main features that were missing and requested : network support and hard disk installation. Take a look at the changes: ;-)<br/><br/>
* Add a runtime subtitle file selector.<br/>
* SysLinux bootloader has been replaced by IsoLinux, providing quicker boot with no more floppy emulation.<br/>
* Add a TCP/IP and network ethernet support and autoconfiguration with DHCP client.<br/>
* Add support and automount for all Windows shares (Samba support).<br/>
* Add support for Leadtek TV2000 remote.<br/>
* Add support for homemade LIRC receivers.<br/>
* Add Italian, Czech and Slovak langage support.<br/>
* Add a new theme (design and boot logo).<br/>
* Add an easy HDD and USB keys installator (just hit <b>install</b> at boot prompt).<br/><br/>

        The GeeXboX's website has also been modified to provide better user's support and faster developement : <br/><br/>
* This website is now accesible from <b><a href="http://www.geexbox.org/">http://www.geexbox.org/</a></b><br/>
* You can now subscribe to the developer mailing list to help for the development or to simply be aware of daily progress.<br/>
* You can get the current development version from CVS.<br/>
      </content>
      <content lang="fr" title="GeeXboX Summer Edition : 0.90-4 (05/08/03)">
        Voici venue la nouvelle version de la GeeXboX ;-) Elle comprend désormais les 2 principales fonctionnalités qui lui manquaient et que vous attendiez tant, à savoir : le support réseau and l'installation sur disque dur. Regardez plus en détails, les changements sont assez conséquents ;-)<br/><br/>
* Ajout d'un menu de sélection dynamique des sous-titres.<br/>
* Le chargeur SysLinux a été remplacé par IsoLinux, permettant un démarrage plus rapide et ne nécessitant plus d'émulation disquette.<br/>
* Ajout du support TCP/IP et des cartes réseaux Ethernet avec configuration automatique via DHCP.<br/>
* Ajout du support et du montage automatique des partages Windows (support Samba).<br/>
* Support de la télécommande Leadtek TV2000.<br/>
* Support des récepteurs LIRC fait-maison.<br/>
* Support des langages Italien, Tchèque et Slovaque.<br/>
* Ajout d'un nouveau thème (design et logo de boot).<br/>
* Ajout d'un installateur rapide pour disques dur et clés USB (tapez simplement <b>install</b> au prompt de démarrage).<br/><br/>

        Le site de la GeeXboX a également subit quelques modifications permettant un meilleur support utilisateur ainsi qu'un développement plus rapide : <br/><br/>
* Le site est désormais accessible depuis l'adresse <b><a href="http://www.geexbox.org/">http://www.geexbox.org/</a></b><br/>
* Vous pouvez désormais souscrire à la liste de diffusion pour développeurs, permettant de participer au développement du système or simplement pour être informé des évolutions journalières.<br/>
* La version en cours de développement est disponible au téléchargement depuis un CVS.<br/>
      </content>
    </subsection>
    <subsection label="release_0.90-3">
      <content lang="en" title="GeeXboX Revolution : 0.90-3 (06/25/03)">
        Seems it has been a while since the last release ;-) But its contents reflect its name ;-) While the overall system hasn't changed much, you'll be pleased to discover all of these new features, for which you've waited so long :<br/><br/>

* Support for multilingual menus.<br/>
* Change the quit/eject scheme.<br/>
* Support for RealMedia 8/9 and Windows Media 9 codecs (needs to regenerate the ISO).<br/>
* Better CD/DVD drives detection.<br/>
* Reduction of the CD's rotation speed.<br/>
* Support for hardware acceleration (vidix) on EPIA 800.<br/>
* Support for on-the-fly image ratio switch.<br/>
* Support for on-the-fly audio streams switch.<br/>
* Support for on-the-fly subtitles switch.<br/>
* Display subtitles in a more traditionnal font.<br/>
* Support for FireWire devices.<br/>
* Support for PcTV, RealMagic, Hauppage, Logitech and especially ATI Remote Wonder remote controllers..<br/>
* No more distinction between EDEN and i586 versions.<br/>
* Partial support for some Plug'n Play ISA sound cards (untested feature).<br/>
* Add an ISO generator, that lets you regenerate a customized ISO (or include a movie) in just a few seconds without building the sources (available under GNU/Linux and Microsoft Windows 9x/NT/2k/XP systems).<br/>
      </content>
      <content lang="fr" title="GeeXboX Revolution : 0.90-3 (25/06/03)">
        On peut dire qu'elle aura pris son temps celle là. Mais son contenu est à la hauteur de son nom ;-) Si le fonctionnement global reste inchangé, vous serez ravis de découvrir tous ces petits plus pour lesquels vous avez tous tant attendu :<br/><br/>

* Support des menus multilangues.<br/>
* Changement de la procédure d'arrêt et d'éjection.<br/>
* Support des codecs RealMedia 8/9 et Windows Media 9 (nécessaire de regénérer l'ISO).<br/>
* Meilleure détection des lecteurs CD/DVD.<br/>
* Réduction de la vitesse de rotation des CD.<br/>
* Support de l'accélération matérielle (vidix) pour les EPIA 800.<br/>
* Support du changement de ratio d'image à la volée.<br/>
* Support du changement du flux audio à la volée.<br/>
* Support du changement de sous-titres à la volée.<br/>
* Affichage des sous-titres dans une police moins extravagante.<br/>
* Support des périphériques FireWire.<br/>
* Support des télécommandes PcTV, RealMagic, Hauppage, Logitech et surtout ATI Remote Wonder.<br/>
* Plus de distinction entre les versions EDEN et i586.<br/>
* Support partiel de certaines cartes sons au format ISA Plug'n Play (non testé).<br/>
* Ajout d'un générateur d'ISO, permettant de regénérer une ISO personnalisée (ou d'y inclure un DivX) en quelques secondes seulement sans recompiler les sources (disponible sous GNU/Linux et Microsoft Windows 9x/NT/2k/XP).<br/>
      </content>
    </subsection>
    <subsection label="release_0.90-2">
      <content lang="en" title="GeeXboX Reloaded : 0.90-2 (05/28/03)">
        So you enjoyed 0.90-1 ? We listened to your requests and a new release has finally arrived. Since the day of the first public release, almost 15000 ISOs have been downloaded. We hope this one will do better. So here is the news :<br/><br/>
* Support for almost all PCI or motherboards integrated soundcards (ISA sound cards are still NOT supported at all).<br/>
* Support for USB Keyboards<br/>
* Support for SCSI CDROM and Disks and Adaptec SCSI controllers.<br/>
* Support for FireWire/IEEE1394 CDROM and Disks (no HotPlug). EDIT : Seems to be broken :-(<br/>
* Support for NTFS FileSystem.<br/>
* Support for S3 Savage cards' TV-Out.<br/>
* No more distinction between Standard and ACPI version.<br/>
* Drives have been renamed for easier understanding.<br/>
      </content>
      <content lang="fr" title="GeeXboX Reloaded : 0.90-2 (28/05/03)">
        Vous avez apprécié la version 0.90-1 ? Nous avons écouté vos requêtes et la nouvelle version est désormais disponible. Depuis le jour de sortie de la première version publique, plus de 15000 ISO ont été téléchargées !! Espérons que cette version fera de même ;-) Voici donc les principaux changements :<br/><br/>
* Support de presque toutes les cartes son PCI ou intégrées à la carte-mère (les cartes sons ISA ne sont toujours pas supportées).<br/>
* Support des claviers USB<br/>
* Support des lecteurs CDROM et disques SCSI ainsi que des controlleurs Adaptec.<br/>
* Support des CDROM et disques FireWire/IEEE1394 (pas de branchement à chaud). EDIT : Semble ne pas fonctionner :-(<br/>
* Support du système de fichiers NTFS.<br/>
* Prise en charge de la sortie TV des cartes S3 Savage.<br/>
* Plus de distinction entre les versions standard et ACPI.<br/>
* Les noms de lecteurs ont été renommés pour plus de compréhension.<br/>
      </content>
    </subsection>
    <subsection label="release_0.90-1">
      <content lang="en" title="GeeXboX First Public Release : 0.90-1 (05/16/03)">
        GeeXboX is a full standalone media player. It's a bootable CD based on Linux which allows you to watch movies or listen to music. It supports most formats, such as MPEG, AVI, DivX, XviD, Ogg/Vorbis (Ogm, Ogg), RealMedia, MP3, DVD, VCD and Audio CD. Here is a few examples of its capabilities : <br/><br/>

* Support for MPEG 1/2 movies (MPG files, VCDs, DVDs ...)<br/>
* Support for MPEG 4 movies (DivX, XviD, FFMpeg ...)<br/>
* Support for OggMedia streams<br/>
* Support for Audio streams like MP3, Ogg/Vorbis, WAV (AudioCD), AC3 ...<br/>
* Support for IR remote controllers<br/>
* Support for ATI and nVidia cards TV-Out<br/>
* Support for subtitled movies<br/>
* Support for media playlist (including WinAmp .m3u)<br/>
* Support for USB Drives<br/>
* Fully customizable with themes.<br/>
* Fully controllable by OSD Menu.<br/>
* Fully bootable Operating System (i.e. you don't need any hard disk to boot).<br/>
<br/>
Don't wait any longer! Just go to the <page name="download"/> Section.<br/>
<br/>
<b>The GeeXboX's Team</b>
      </content>
      <content lang="fr" title="GeeXboX First Public Release : 0.90-1 (16/05/03)">
        La GeeXboX est un lecteur multimédia autonome. C'est en fait un CD auto-amorçable, basé sur un noyau Linux, vous permettant de visionner des films ou d'écouter de la musique. Elle supporte de très nombreux formats, comme par exemple les MPEG, AVI, DivX, XviD, Ogg/Vorbis (Ogm, Ogg), RealMedia, MP3, DVD, VCD et autres CD Audio. Voici quelques exemples de l'étendue de ces capacités : <br/><br/>

* Support des vidéos de type MPEG 1/2 (fichiers .MPG , VCDs, DVDs ...)<br/>
* Support des vidéos MPEG 4 (DivX, XviD, FFMpeg ...)<br/>
* Support des flux OggMedia <br/>
* Support des flux audio exclusifs tels que le MP3, l'Ogg/Vorbis, les .WAV (CD Audio), AC3 ...<br/>
* Support des télécommandes infra-rouges<br/>
* Support de la sortie TV des cartes graphiques ATI et nVidia <br/>
* Support des films sous-titrés<br/>
* Support des listes de lecture (incluant les .m3u de WinAmp par exemple)<br/>
* Support des lecteurs externes au format USB <br/>
* Entièrement personnalisable à l'aide de nombreux thèmes<br/>
* Entièrement controlable à l'aide du menu interractif à l'ecran (OSD)<br/>
* Système d'exploitation complet (i.e. ne nécessite pas de disque dur d'installé pour démarrer).<br/>
<br/>
N'attendez plus, dirigez vous vers la Section de <page name="download"/>.<br/>
<br/>
<b>L'équipe GeeXboX</b>
      </content>
    </subsection>
  </section>
</article>
